Weeell.What do broadcasters promise us for tomorrow?
Weeell...The comrades broadcasters promise us tomorrow 20 degrees. Above 0, so not bad..Changing cloudness, warm wind north-west.
For somebody going to be bright, for somebody not..The weather in Piter is changing with a cosmic speed.
And with it changes the mood. So for the emotion stabilization, breathe deep and stay on our line, it's an excellent place by the way. Stand here, don't move..
And..let's get acquainted: Me, Masha Emelianova and you are listening to
Maybe something from a new collection?..
Cool, isn't it?..Very good choice..
You like?..
No?
Tell me, why are all these mannequins bald?
..You don't know?? It is a new style! The last fashion tendency!
Yes my sweet, yes honey..What we are doing? Drawing little pretty houses
Which beer? No, I'm alone..
Which Ira?
Here you are..
Colour.
Voice.
Taste.
Interesting girl..
Everyday for you..Masha Emelianova
Piter FM on air.
And we're continuing our concert.
Fedor and Victor are congratulating their friend Maxim Vasiliev on winning an international competition of young architects.
Maxim came to be best of the best.
And attention!
He's leaving for Berlin!!
Max, you've heard?
But this is the official version, but I think Mr. Vasiliev is going there for beer. Don't forget, Maxim, beer makes the tummy grow.
Uph, guys, well..thanks.
Do you know any German girls?..
Of course. Clara Tsetkin..
Sings cool..
I also can sing like that..
Hi, Mashka!
Hi!
The soul is singing?..
What's that?
Is that Our format??
..Yeah.. Changing our orientation..
Mash, I just can't understand..what for you are searching for trouble? Let them listen for their Kirkorov (pop). They like it..
And I don't..
And why are you late?
This wedding..,
Listen Lera, can you replace me for an hour, we have to buy rings with Kostia..
Nee.. I'm dying..
Just one hour, please.
Ok, but Only one hour..Promise!..
It is cool now in Berlin.
In Berlin it is always cool..
Why you go? Why not me instead?..
Don't be jealous so loudly,OK?..
Who is jealous?
He doesn't speak even a bit of German! Tell Gastarbeiter, tell gastarbeiter!
And the mansard? You'll leave it to me?
And you'll work as a street-cleaner?
..No.
And Marina, is she aware already?
And when you are going to organize you farewell night?
..Tomorrow..
No, I'm serious..
Then the day after tomorrow
Mmm.what to eat to lose weight?
Attention! Mortal trick!
Recognizing the handwriting of Master.
Is it undangerous for life?..
Don't know, but Kostia likes that..
Have you already fed Krosha?
..Oh, I forgot. Have a snack, my little.
I love you..
Me too.
Who are you?
Saniok. I'm listening to your voice every day. You are so..
So what?
You are simply crazy..super.Tell me honey how do you look like?
Eye-colour, size..
Oh, my sweet, thanks to be direct!
Ciao, hear you some other time!..
Who's that?
Awful.
Fans don't leave in peace?
..Maniacs..!
Careful!
Come here
What?
You see that one, with flowers?..Mine..
Funny! What's the name?
Dima I think..Yesterday hardly got rid of him. Waiting..Knows that my ephire ended
Emelianova, after the programme to my room!..
So.. putting Kirkorov..
..Yeah..
..Hello, Masha?.. Sorry..
Hi
Hi..Where have you been? I'm here for half an hour..
I could not come before really..
You hired a secretary?
What you mean?
I don't know ..What the man is answering your phone?
Damn..
Yeah, even a week did not pass.
I didn't even notice..
I gave you a new Samsung.
Don't put it on I asked you..
Give me your phone.
You'll lose it as well?
..Of course.
Hi, my phone is in good hands?
Yes, Masha, you are lucky.
How do you know my name?
There've been calls only to Masha..
And your name?
Maxim. How can I give it back to you?
You know, today I could come to meet you at about 9 pm, under the monument.
Ok, how I'll recognize you?
Easily, I'll be dressed in a Hare costume.
Joking..Can I call you later?
Yes, of course.
..What happened?
Nothing.
Where is again my fault?
Nothing..
Otello! A real moor!
Let's go buy rings, otherwise I'll be late for job..
Take off this horror from your head..
Take it off, I'll throw it away..
As for me I like it...
I'm delighted.
You are very talented.
Invitation. Go to the consulate tomorrow morning!
Contract. You have 2 days to study it..
Sorry..
Yes Marina..
Yes I called,
when you can take your things? Ok,
today, at what time?
At 10.00?..
Yes Masha. A second..Yes Marina, You have the keys? Okay. Sorry. Can not speak right now.
Hello, yes Masha. Yes..So I can recognize you by..?
A birthmark on your back?
..Yes, I can wait..Sorry..
Women..Isn't it a pity for you to leave them?
I understand..
I'll have a red jacket ..Not tall..
Okay..See you.
Who's that?
I lost my mobile..He found..
Now wants to give it back.
Is he good-looking?
And this is the thing I didn't ask..
And does he know that you work on the radio? No..
Don't say.. This Dima got me already.
Calls every day, invites to the cinema. He's nice but I don't know....What you think. Shall I go?..
Lera. Simple. If you want you go, don't want don't go. And give back the disc. .
.If only I could know..I want or I don't want..
Me too..
And you what?..
nothing..
The rings..You bought?
Yeah 2
Show!
Kostia took them
Right, you'd lose them.
He told the same..
Happy you are, Mashka
..Lera..They all went crazy with this wedding..Running,organizing..Mothers both making lists, bouquets..
Oh, at the wedding aim at me with your bouquet!
People meet..
People fall in love..Get married..
And for example..if there existed not only two sexes but all five! And to survive they would need to come all together. 1 got ill, 2nd is late, 3rg lost his way, 4th simply changed his mind,
and it turns out that for love only the 5th is ready. And what can he do, alone?
How cool it is as a result that there are only men and women. To those who are in love devoted..
Hello, why so late? I work till 7.
Here is the dismission paper, I need you to sign it.
Which dismission? I will not sign anything like that!
I don't have people to work. Who is going to work? Pushkin?...
I don't know anything..
For the reason of changing for a new job..Which job?
I'm leaving the country..
No I will not sign it..
I'm an architect, I can not all my life clean the streets.
And what! I studied in the SeaFlot Institute!
Tatiana Petrovna, I have the last argument..
I need to leave on Monday, I need all the papers..Take..
Thank you very much..
Welcome very much
And me I'm proud that I'm a cleaner..A cleaner is a not a human or what?
A humain..
Okay..Run..Run, just don't fall!
Sorry, you are Masha?..
Sorry I got mistaken..
You must understand Miss Emelianova..This is a commercial step. Thanks to you, we will lose everything..!
This is the last precaution to you! Go now!
And stop being late for your job!...
Nothing new..As always..
Give me ur hand.
Make a simple face..
Simplier..
Even simplier..
Easier now?
Yup
That's cool..
Listen, what time is it now?..
Sorry, just your jacket..
Why jacket? You want without jacket?
..No..no sorry..I got wrong..
Hi..
how are you?
As usual sitting here and waitin for you..
You want some tea?..
Trying to find my pictures in your garbage...
Tell ,why did you bring all these strange streetsigns? I don't understand..
Where have you been?
At work.
Was it difficult to call?
Not difficult..
I prepared dinner. Waiting for you..
I'm leaving for Germany. You've heard?..
Yes I've heard.
I don't hear the congratulations.
I'm very happy for you..Germany..is cool..
Simply..I'm so tense and busy now..
Head breaking..
Something happened?
No, nothing happened..
I'm getting married that's maybe why..You didn't know?
No..
So that's clear..married..
How was the work?
Good..
And in details..?
..Can I keep silence..Kostia..
I got tired of speaking at work.
Taste the food..Mm..delicious..Taste..
I'm really not hungry..
Something wrong Masha?
You need to go..?
Yeah, I go..
Sorry..
Bye
You remember ..in the 1st class you also had a grey suite?
I've known you almost for all my life..
What an horror..
What u mean..
Marusya..Let's sleep..
Tomorrow my parents asked me to pass by..They have hundred of things to do..
Maxim, sorry.
You seemed not to wait till the end for me..
I waited for one hour..
I was overheld at work..
You could also call
..Sorry..I'll try not to be late anymore.
Simply all fell on me the same time..
This wedding, this work..
Also getting married?
Why also?
Don't know..Fashionable now..
I called at the wrong moment?
It's ok.
You have a such a voice..No..simply all fell on me also..
I'm leaving for Berlin in 3 days.
For long?..
For very..
Cool! I would go somewhere also now.
In Berlin it's nice they say.
I'm not bad here also.
So why you go then?
Don't know..didn't decide yet. Try to throw the coin. One side yes one side no..
Masha..
I do it sometimes.
Thanks for advice..
So where and when?
Are you disposable at 11 am tomorrow?
Yes, where?
Let's meet at Gorkovskaya, close to the underground-pass, under the clock.
Okay..Red jacket..I'll wear the blue one.
Masha, can you describe youself?
Mmm..I'm a rare beauty..
Eyes grey-blue..untidy hair..golden teeth..
Joking..So..Ok?
I like it..
Till tomorrow.
Bye..
Damn..
I think we got cheated with Limouzin.
Kostia..
Mash!
What is that? You promised me not to wear that!
And what is this lipstick?
..Like that it's better?
What happens honey?
Honey, let's not quarrel for little things ok? You know me, I'm always like that.
You wanted to tell me something?
..Sorry..That's just nerves.
Hello Marina. That's me..I hope I didn't wake you up?
Veery good..
Listen, I found your pictures here. Ready to give them back. Let's meet somewhere.
You are giving them to me?
Then..that's all..
I say thank you..
THANK YOU..Sorry, I can not speak right now..
Nothing precious?
..No..
I hope you understand. That's really important for me.
I understand..There was a little difficulty..
Kostia! Kostia! I need to go.
Yes..we are going..
You understand that this is Wedding, that this is important..
Look, Marina!
You fulfil all my conditions. If not I take my money back and go to another company. Okay?
..Understood
Miss!Miss! Wait...!
My god what is it? I can not..I'm being late!
Miss, I can not run after you, my shoe broke..
Yes..
Ouph, I feel pain..
Tell me, does sex with a stranger interest you?
No.
I felt it..
At least you maybe Will give me your number?
No..
Give me your number, if not I'll get an alcoholic completely.
Miss, beauty! wait! Give me a number..
I don't have a phone..!
Cruel!
My son, my son! I'm begging you! Can you help me to count..
did they give me the right change? The bread costs 6.20 and I gave 10.00..
Wait..the bread 6.20..
Yes..
and I gave 10.00.Where are 6.20..?
On filling this form you can make a free phone call to any world point for free..
Thank you..
What are the flowers?
Liziantuses..
Then I take those ones..
Cakes, Chebureki, Hotdogs Red Beauty..
Sorry, have you seen a young man in a blue jacket here. He must wait for me here.
Of course. Look around..how many there are here..Choose any..
Sorry have you seen a girl in a red jacket..
There are many in red jackets..Blonde, dark?
She told she had golden teeth, untidy hair..
Good afternoon..
Registration..In order..
Armor, drugs..?
No, thank you..
Joke, joke...
Daughter, my daughter, can you help me to count?
I gave 10.00 for bread and it costs 6.20..
Thank you my dear..God blesses you, health to you and a good husband..
This is for you..
For me? Thank you..
Late again!..Everyone is already nervous..Felix is furious.
Be in tonus and don't be late for your dates. And now we are listening some slow music..
Hi girls.
Water..
How did you get there?
First by fire-ladder then by cornice..I came to see Lera actually.
Can you go to the cinema with me?...
..Okay..
And I have super news! According to folk superstitions, If somebody got to you through the window the day promises to be excellent, and this is true. Proven on people. You are listening to Piter FM, everything will be alright
Hello, something happened?
Mr., you got dismissed from your job and why you are not leaving the flat?
I am going..Is it urgent?
Very urgent. Very..
I just wanted to ask ..Maybe to wait..one week or two?
You seem not to understand..Tomorrow we are going to do inventarisation here and the day after tomorrow our new worker moves in. You must understand..It's not just my wish..
I understand..
No you don't..Tomorrow we don't work..So we must fill this list today..
How to fill it in? Which place to mention?..Where is he from?
I'm from Nizhnii Novgorod. Wait..
What wait..You understand that the passport office works only till 6 today, so we have time to sigh you out..Do we?
So pack your things, give your keys..
I am leaving on Monday,
Where I'm going to live till then?
..And about this I don't care at all
..Okay..Okay..i don't sign anything.
I don't have any place to go. Will sit here till Monday.
Eh, don't bull! We speak kindly with him, and he's bulling!
Sign! ..So we are going to use the hands..??
Ah! You say you will sit until Monday, you WILL sit, be sure!
Such a pig's mess 've made in the flat. What a shame!
The sun came out and I've got a feeling that the population of the city increased by 3 times as minimum.
The statistics say in Piter there live about 6 mln people.
Personally I saw today for sure 18 mln. So many people..
And the one needed, the only one, is lost again.
The sponsor of our programme is the Ritual Service 'Way to Yourself'. The wonderful solution of all your problems. Haha..
They dig deep ah..Superslogan.
See you in a moment.
You are crazy?!You imagine what's going to happen now?
..Hello, Emelianova! Now now stop this horror, immediately!
Sorry, is it possible to arrange it all quickly? I'm really in a hurry.
..What does your 'quicker' mean..quicker than in 15 days doesn't come already. Fight..with insulting the administration..
It can hardly be called a fight.. There are witnesses..You are going abroad..
Yes, this is the contract, I'm an architect.
And in the working paper it's written a street-cleaner.
And why 2 phones? Stolen?
..Why stolen..one is mine, one is of my girlfriend's.
And where's Maxim? In the police office N8.
And why?
Arrested.
Masha Emelianova..Have you known him for a long time?..
Yes, I'm his fiancée.
And why your mobile is on him?..
I gave it to him myself. Tell me please, when are you going to let him?
..The court will decide..
Which court? Wait, wait!
Goodbye..
Nice voice has your girlfriend..
Hello, Petre Efimovich!
You remember me?..
Yes of course! I really need your help, one young man got into trouble..Oh, wait.
Good afternoon, Mr. General!
Good afternoon Mayor.
In your office now there is my relative, Maxim Vasiliev.
A guy hooliganned a bit..
but now realized everything ..
You have been a Mayor long..?
The 3rd year Mr. General..
For long..
Water..!!
Mine..Student..Beauty..Figure, clever..everything Doesn't smoke, doesn't drink alcohol.
..Ill?
..Why ill??
..Don't know..doesn't smoke, doesn't drink..
She is not ill..Simply so faithful..
Vasiliev, out!
Thanks God. Hi, what happened?
I'll tell you. I don't know what you told them but they let me out.
Imagine I told the police that you are my fiancé. That's ok?
That's terribly.pleasant.
What are you doing? ..
Sitting, watching the house. Beautiful? ..
No, ugly.
You'll show it to me when we meet?
Ok, but not today..
Today's my farewell party.
Me too I'm working tonight. I'll call you ok?
Ok..will be waiting..Thank you one more..
Here you can call and share your happiness or your sadness..The next call is on..Good evening.
How to tell a man that I don't love him anymore..
You are sure in that?
Yes..he's very kind and good and he loves me..But I know if I tell him he will feel bad. I'm so tensed Don't know what to do.
..That's complicated.
I believe the most important thing is honesty.
If you will kill me I'll understand..
We will see..Kostia. Good that you are here. Masha is coming. Listen, she's not very ok today..
We have some changes..From now on you are going to put one song of this disc at the end of every hour. And in the breaks you speak about the group.Here you can find everything.
Sorry but I can not put in on air!
You can take me out of the radio, but this is pornography, and people listen.
No..I'm not going to take you out. All will be much simplier.
I will close this circus.
You finish this shift and you are fired!
This is for you.
Thank you..For what?
I was wrong sorry.
Maybe we'll not argue anymore.
Parents gave me the list of guests for approval.
Excuse me..
don't you remember the song of Grebenschikov about the phone?..
No..not this!
I told you!
Kostia.
There will be no wedding.
What? What the jokes!
I did not understand..
I can not..
Kostia understand me please..You are very good..You are the closest person I have..
Everything will be ok..
Don't say silly things.
I don't love you
Forgive me
That's all right
One big grey metal bird
flew flew, flew flew..and fell down!
That's why we project houses and not the planes..
They of course fall, but at least don't fly..
For you Max! For your brilliant future!
I love Piter actually..
I hardly believe in such patriotism.
You didn't understand why? Because of Marina..
I'm the same believe me..You remember with Galia?
He's so sad..Marina..The architect needs a musa.
Ready? Recording?
Hi..
You have a cigarette?
Thanks brother...
Wife bitch..Doesn't let me in..
Take..
Thank you brother..
You want?
No..
Right..Only problems of this vodka..
She sent me to do shopping with a list.. And today is weekend, I bought also a little vodka and a beer.
Drank all, and put the bottles into the bag..
and to close forgot!! And all split on this damned food..
She made a scandal, doesn't let me in now
.bitch..
all of them they are bitches..to kill her that's all
.Eh..eh guy where are you going?..jacket!..
Marina..
take the phone..
Sorry for calling so late. Nobody called during the day?
Nobody.
I see..What is this sound, where are you?
..Sitting on the bridge..
Romantics..
Heh..
And what is there, on the bridge?
..On the bridge? Awfully cold, Water flowing, fog..chunky dog running..
I want also on the bridge..
I can reserve a place for you.
Ah, in the afternoon some guy called..
Kostia, maybe..
Your fiancé?
And when is the wedding?..
You are crying?
He'll call..
Sorry..
That's ok..Simply there will be no wedding..
Quarelled?..
We've been together a huge time, from school. He's good. I don't know what happened but
I realized suddenly that I can not anymore..Told him today.
Sorry for him..Though..Don't pity him. My girlfriend left me too, no pity. And you see, surviving somehow..
Sad..
And what can we do..Life is in general an unexpected thing..Only in movies everything is predictable.
..And you promised to show me the house.
I'll show. I have a special relation with buildings.
Which relation?
I'm an architect..
They all like people..Sometimes they tell you such things..can write romans from that..
Do you write?
No..lazy..
Piter is full of such stories..
And you are going to leave..You decided to go?
..Until the moment I give you the phone I'll not go don't worry..
So, you'll have to stay for long..
You know I didn't make up my mind yet..maybe it's better to leave.
Threw the coin? Yes..everywhere..in both rivers..
See you tomorrow?
Of course.
Strange..You have such a voice..As if I heard it many times before..
Maybe..Good night Maxim.
Good night Masha..
Signed the contract? Everything is satisfying your demands?
No..Point 27..I can not agree on that.
Ah..you don't understand what it is forcemajor?
This is zunami, earthquake, revolution, this is only formality..
How come..the earthquake the formality..You know that the next years there can happen plenty of zunamis, as Naustradamus saw..No, I can not work in such conditions.
I'm asking you..This is the standard point of every contract..
I'm begging you. Come in a couple of days..Think everything over..
I will not sign this contract , BUT I can recommend you a very good architect, Fedor Zemtsov.
I'll write his number to you.
Call him please, he is a very talented young architect.
And what is very important
he is not afraid neither of zunami, nor of earthquakes, nor of revolutions.
Listen, this radio killer called you himself?
..Yeah..
Haha I beg he is not indifferent to you..
Wait a second.
I'll tell you by secret, that broadcasters promise rain today..
though..who belives broadcasters nowadays..
On the other hand..why the rain is bad..Maybe it's even better..
Hi Masha! Very glad to hear you!
Yeah I'd like to meet you very much too. Let's meet today.
Listen, let me have your number 'cause your battery is running out..
Good afternoon..
Good afternoon I would like to leave a message for a girl named Masha, in a red jacket who lost her phone..
Maxim, is it you..?