Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
I'm sick of your music!
Turn down the volume.
Turn it down!
It turned out
you are good in women.
Well, at least betterthan you are.
Women don't have will-power,
thanks God.
I don't have will-power?
Don't worry,
I'll put you in your place.
I hope I'm at my place already.
You can hope.
- You'll get it in the neck.
- I'm kidding.
Pull over.
- I'm starting. Note the time.
- Go. I'll be watching.
- Have I ever lied to you?
- But don't turn off your phone.
And you don't call every minute.
The Stroll
No, you can't.
And why?
Because I don't give
my names to strangers.
And you are right in that.
Giving names to strangers
is too flippantly, it's a bad form
and I would even say
that it's vulgarity.
What beautiful eyes you have!
What's your name?
I'm not telling you.
If you want I can call you Stranger.
Do you know,
there is a picture with such name.
It's now being printed
in candy's wrapping.
Actually,
you can see it here in a museum.
It's not "Stranger", it's "Unknown".
And it's not here, it's in Moscow,
in Tretyakovskaya Gallery.
As always, everything what's good
is in Moscow. Like a tragedy.
At least I can console, that girls
in our city are more intelligent.
- Me?
- Yes, you.
Do you study or work?
I'm just walking.
My name is Alexey.
Do you mind having a company?
I love walking with mysterious ladies.
- Maria suits you. Maria, the name.
- Maria?
I'd call you Mary.
No my name is Olya, as simple as that.
Olga, Olga, Olga.
Something very ancient.
Some queens, Tatar incursions,
a long narrow river,
sad songs of the north people.
- Let's go to the north, Olga.
- To the north?
We'll be in fur and hide
and I'll show you a passionate dance.
Slow it down.
- You talk too much.
- Maybe.
You don't have to show off.
I'm already walking with you.
- Let's be informal.
- What a wonderful idea!
I didn't dare to ask that first.
- Where are we going to?
Just walking.
I like just walking and looking around.
The weather is great.
I don't see anything what is
worthy of special attention.
All attention is paid to certain Olya.
- Do you see a man in a red T-shirt?
- Yes.
He's waving his hands.
I've been watching him for a long time.
- He is a complete idiot.
- You really think so?
- Wanna try?
- OK. Let's.
Excuse me.
- Hello.
- Would you like to go to a theatre?
- With you, babe?
- Where are you going, baby?
- Sorry, good bye.
It's really impressing.
- Are you always so good in people?
- Almost.
Can you say something
about this woman in the light skirt?
Of course.
Lazy, untidy, a mess in herflat.
She thinks about meeting her prince.
- How do you know that?
- Do you see unshaved legs?
That means she is lazy, untidy,
not interested in men who surround her,
varicose veins,
that means she gave a birth.
And she's wearing a white skirt, because
she wants to attract men's attention.
How did you know
she had scandals with her husband?
Just my imagination.
Maybe that was her reason of divorce.
She is not
an interesting subject to talk about.
- What did you think about me?
- About you?
You are funny, foppish,
like to be in the centre of attention.
Then, there was something else
what I thought about you.
- What was that?
- Not gonna tell you.
- Come on, tell me.
- I won't. You'd get offended.
- I won't. Please tell me.
- No.
You are not lucky with girls.
- You're right.
- You see?
- How did you guess?
- Somehow.
You just fall in love with wrong ones.
I have a friend, Petyunya,
he is very easy.
He tells me, that I sense bitches.
- Are you a bitch?
- No, I'm a very nice girl.
- But, of course, I have some bitching.
- I appreciate your honesty.
Hey, what do you think about yourself?
- About myself?
- Yes.
- I like dreaming.
- And what do you dream about?
- I pretend to be sugar.
- Swimming in a glass?
No. Like I am a brick of sugar.
Very refractory, hard.
I'm in hot tea or coffee
and I start melting.
I go to the bottom, I lie there,
merge with water, sweeten the drink.
And one can also break me with a spoon.
I hate when people do that.
When they try to break me
in the bottom of the glass.
- I hate it.
- Why do you hate that? Can you explain?
It's not me who hates it.
The sugar hates it.
- Are you serious?
- You think I'm sick?
One day, when I was taking a bath
I pretended to be Bill Clinton.
What? What were you doing?
I was divorcing Hillary
and marrying Monica.
Monica is fat.
So what? We live in London,
play saxophone, dance salsa.
You can't imagine how good that is!
Of course I understand, I'm old
enough, but I still can do things!
By the way, Monica presented
a bike to my birthday.
It's a great think.
We were riding along the city.
By the way, my hair gets grey.
People say, grey hair looks good to me.
The only thing which
worries me is my daughter, Chelsea.
She is a unique child.
She doesn't understand anything.
She is on mother's side. I tried to
talk to her, but she doesn't understand.
Why are you laughing?
Stop laughing.
Everybody dreams about that,
but not everybody admits that.
When I was a child
I wanted to be a traffic-controller.
- And you?
- I wanted to draw lines on roads.
Those which are at crossings.
Beautiful dream.
Beautiful. I understand you.
Do you dream about anything now?
I don't know. I don't think so.
But I always interview myself.
Recently I gave a press conference
about developing of Russian economics.
It was broadcasted on all TV channels
and newspapers quoted that too.
And, by the way, it was in a bath too.
You are like me.
My congratulations. You are sick too.
- You are an amazing girl.
- I agree.
Let's drink something.
Let's sit somewhere, I'll call Petya.
I must introduce him
such a wonderful girl.
Are you talking about the one
who calls girls bitches?
You can introduce me to him,
but I won't go to any place.
Firstly, I don't drink,
secondly, I can't sit.
Do you have piles?
Very funny.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean that.
It was idiotic.
- Stupid and boorish.
- I'm sorry, but why can't you sit?
I won't tell you to spite you.
- Please, tell me.
- I won't.
Please.
I can't sit,
because I fell off a horse.
- Say what? Fell off a horse?
- I injured my spinal column.
Now I have to walk a lot
and I can't sit.
- Do you work in a circus?
- You starting it again?
No, really.
No, I do equestrian sport.
I'm a jockey.
Ah, it's when horses dance?
- Yes, yes.
- Great.
And those who sit
on horses have crooked legs.
- What?
- Don't be mad.
Nonsense.
What's the name of the horse?
Diamond. It's a stallion.
I had Rook before him.
He was written off. He was old.
Is it your phone or mine?
I think it's mine.
Hello. Hi. Wait.
Yes.
Yes. As we agreed.
OK. Bye.
- May I ask you a tactless question?
- Shoot.
- Who was that?
- My coach, Vsevolod Maksimych.
- Your coach?
- Yes.
Why were you so informal with him?
I've been known him since my childhood.
We all are informal with each other.
It's a very rude world.
- And you curse too?
- Sometimes.
And you thought I'm a modest girl.
I think such girls are artificial.
Like in old books when
old ladies fainted away.
All my life I dreamt to faint away.
I wish to feel dizziness
just once in my life. Never.
- I feel so bad right now. Wait.
- Olya, what's happened?
- I don't know what it is.
- Do you have a stomach-ache?
Did you buy it? Yes?
It's a way how to fool men.
You believe in everything.
These pigeons went crazy.
You think, that we, girls,
only wash up in a bathroom?
Actually, I don't wanna know
in details what you do there.
How are you gonna live with your wife?
Do you think
she's gonna go to neighbours?
You seem to be too experienced.
Are you married?
Oh, no. Don't wanna be married.
Why?
- Because I like being with myself.
- And with me?
With you?
Well, it's OK.
- So marry me then.
- What did you say?
You know what, let's do that
in... 14 minutes.
- Why in 14?
- Why not?
Are you kidding again
oryou are serious?
Actually, people don't say
such things to little known men.
- Do you believe in love at first sight?
- Of course not.
Where are you going?
Mister policeman,
do you believe in love at first sight?
Do you believe
in love at first sight or not?
Are you OK?
I want to know if our law machinery
believes in love at first sight.
- You see?
- Don't take it seriously.
I saw her and fell in love at once.
But she doesn't believe me.
I fell in love and forgot
about my stupid heart.
By the way, do you have a stupid heart?
- Don't take it seriously.
- Does he botheryou?
Ljust want to know if our law machinery
believes in love at first sight.
Do you believe in it or not.
Answer, please.
- Are you drunk?
- Drunk with love.
- Do you believe?
- I do, I do. Get going.
Thank you, mister policeman.
Thank you very much.
- Marry me.
- You are crazy.
There are so many people here.
I don't care about these people.
Just marry me.
- Are you crazy?
- Marry me.
I can't understand if you're a fool
oryou are miserable.
I feel foryou of course,
but that's not enough for marriage.
Are you crazy? What marriage?
Maybe you agree on romance?
Who asks such things?
Of course I'd like
to have a friendship with you,
but I don't believe in friendship
between a man and a woman.
And besides, you are very beautiful
and I wanna kiss you.
And I don't wanna kiss Petya,
that means this is not a friendship.
Let me kiss you.
- No.
- Please.
I don't want that.
You'd better introduce me to that Petya.
You mention her every 5 minutes.
Her? Not a problem.
- I can call him right now if you want.
- OK.
Afriend would never leave
anotherfriend in troubles.
What? That means you are in troubles?
- Olya.
- Good bye then.
That was a joke, Olya.
Why are you so touchy?
Stop it. I hate that Petya.
I hate him.
I'm calling him, I'm calling him.
You're gonna like him.
He's a nice guy.
What are you gonna do
if I like him more than you expect?
- I hope it won't happen.
- But if that happens?
It won't happen, you can't like him,
because you like me.
Do you have
otherfriends besides Petya?
Friends? No. Many acquaintances,
but only one friend.
And what about you?
Rook was my friend.
Rook? A horse?
No, it's not a horse.
It was betterthan a man.
He was very attentive and loving.
He was always funny, naive.
He always protected me.
It's something, when a horse
is your best friend and not a man.
People are the real animals.
- You are so cruel.
- I'm not cruel.
How dare you to censure me?
If I'm cruel or not.
This is too much.
- I'm mad at you.
- I meant that you can love people too.
- Do it if you want.
- Why are you so mad?
I'm not mad any more.
Go where you were going.
- Olga, stop it, please.
- I won't stop it.
- I can be mad too.
- What at?
At your boorishness, for example.
- Boorishness?
- Yes.
Forgive me for being boorish.
I didn't mean to.
And you forgive me.
Are we OK?
- It's so hard with you as it occurred.
- Who said it was gonna be easy?
Let's try to avoid such arguments
in the future.
Tell me what annoys you
and I'll try not to do that.
Nothing annoys me.
Ljust don't like being judged.
If we don't fight,
how are we gonna make it up?
What do you mean?
Just as I said. The process
of making up is also a pleasant one.
Relationship
becomes tenderer and warmer.
Then let's fight again.
I demand a scandal!
- No, I can't.
- Right now!
- How can I offend you?
- You don't have to offend me.
I'll tell you, that you are stupid.
No. Being stupid means
to understand the world differently.
To be stupid is pleasant.
Then I'll call you a smart.
It wouldn't scare me either.
Then I'll tell you,
that we are having a fight,
that I'm upset, disconsolate, unhappy.
I am hurt.
- Start making it up.
- I won't.
- Be closerto me.
- No.
Closer and tenderer!
Otherwise I'll die.
I can die, you know?
I'm dying, I'm dying!
God, I'm dying.
God, Olga, I'm dying.
Olya, let me kiss you, let me kiss you.
This is not we were agreed to.
Let me kiss you, let me kiss you.
She doesn't want to kiss,
she doesn't want to marry.
What a girl I found!
Leave me alone. Stop it, stop it!
Put me on the floor!
I can't be hung.
Do you want an ice-cream?
- What do you want?
- What do I want?
Guess.
Another kiss?
One at a time.
- Your lips are so soft.
- Why? They should be hard?
- Horses have the softest lips.
- You're starting it again.
I'm in love as a pelican
and she's talking about horses.
Why as a pelican?
- Why not?
- Why?
As ill luck would have it,
I gotta go to Moscow today.
I was only once in Moscow.
- Maybe I shouldn't go there today?
- Why? You have to go.
- Let's go together.
- Are you crazy?
Come on, I have friends there,
it's gonna be fun.
There is a booking office overthere.
Let's go.
- No.
- Come on. It'd be great!
- It's not convenient foryou.
- Who told you that?
- Really, I can't.
- Why can't you?
Olya, you are the best girl
in Russian Federation.
I've been known you forfive minutes.
We'll go to a club, it's gonna be fun.
- It's a big challenge for me.
- Yes, it is. A very nice one.
Let's go, you won't regret! Please.
- I feel awkward.
- Why do you feel awkward?
Olya, please.
Let's go, Olya.
Please, say "yes".
Stop it. I don't like
standing in queues. Go alone.
- Give me your passport.
- Why?
- You don't wanna show me your age.
- I don't wanna.
- You don't?
- No.
Give me your passport.
You won't look at it, will you?
- Do you promise?
- Yes, I do.
Here it is.
Be here, wait for me.
I have a friend there, she'll help me.
- OK, go.
- Promise not to leave.
I promise. You have my passport.
- You sure you won't leave?
- Go.
Hello. Daddy, why did you call?
Don't do that anymore.
OK, as we agreed. I have one.
In a minute. I'm almost there.
Where've you been? Why do you call?
Catherine the First came by.
I'm gonna be here, Menshikov is
on the third, Elizabeth on the fourth.
Why me? Why should I be on the fourth?
No one takes pictures there.
Send herthere.
Why do you always fight?
Every day the same.
Catherine should be at the Hermitage.
And what about Elizabeth?
OK, let's go.
What's the difference?
People always confuse us.
I'm on the fourth.
I don't like your attitude!
- Did you buy them?
- Sure.
Then give my passport back.
So we are going at 12
in a compartment car,
but in different compartments.
Don't be mad at me forthat.
Aren't we gonna meet Petya?
Do you want that?
I can call him if you want.
OK.
I want that very much.
It's weird. We're going to Moscow
and I don't know anything about you.
Hello. What are you doing?
- Go to Dvorcovaya Square.
- It's OK.
Can you be there in 30 minutes?
OK. Bye.
You're gonna meet
a very beautiful girl.
- Stop it.
- OK. See you.
He'll come.
- Great.
- Do you need the ticket?
OK. Give it to me.
- Why?
- Give it.
Lyosha, please don't argue.
- OK?
- What's the matter?
Please, take my money forthe ticket.
- Kidding?
- I'm not.
I can't explain the reason,
but I can't go at your expense.
Are you a feminist?
- Even if I were. Why?
- Olya, I earn enough.
I can afford myself
to go to Moscow.
Olya, take away the money.
No doubts that you earn enough.
I understand that.
Please. I can't explain the reason.
Eitheryou take the money
or I'm not going.
Are you crazy?
I told you I earn enough.
- And besides you hurt my feelings.
- I do?
Yes, you do.
I can't explain why.
Take the money, or I'm not going.
Olya, stop showing
your money in the street.
I'm not going?
That means I'm not going?
- Olya, did I invite you?
- Yes.
- You refused?
Bye.
I really want to go to Moscow with you.
Please understand me.
Take the money forthe ticket,
but in Moscow I'll be supported by you.
I promise.
- You promise?
- Yes, I won't open my purse.
OK. Deal.
- What meaning of this?
- There is no meaning.
I'll take this money
and put it in my pocket.
After we come back
I'll return it to you.
- If you don't take it...
- OK.
Why do you always argue with me?
Why do we always
sort out our relationship?
Forget it. Stop being mad.
I promise,
everything's gonna be perfect.
It's like we're in Paris now,
do you hearthe music?
- Have you been to Paris?
- No.
Don't play too loud.
I can't hear anything.
- I'm working.
- So am I.
Can you shut up?
I don't hear myself.
Boor.
Dear citizens and guests...
I'll show you
citizens and guests after all...
Continue playing, Beethoven.
- We invite you for a wonderful trip...
- How long are you gonna do that?
..by our comfortable bus.
- OK, I got it.
- Hello.
- Who is that?
- Who is it?
- Hi, Mom.
I remember, I'll be there soon.
Isn't that Rook?
Rook!
- My dear Rook. Hi. My dear!
- Do want to have a ride?
Olya, where are you going?
- Did you miss me?
- Let's have a ride.
- Don't be afraid.
- Come on, let me help you.
You make money with his help?
- He is a nice guy.
- Who let you take him forthat?
- Have a ride.
- Is it good making money using him?
And you think
you don't need to take care of him?
- Look at his teeth.
- Don't touch him.
- You don't touch him!
- Leave us alone!
- Leave us!
- Are you crazy?
- I have taken care of him for 8 years.
- What are you talking about?
- And you're making money using him!
- Stop it, Olya!
I'll call in the club.
Calm down, maybe it's not Rook.
Maybe he looks like him.
I have taken care of him for 8 years.
Calm down, don't cry.
Don't worry, nobody's riding him.
Nobody's making money using him.
He's fed. He's a nice horse.
Olya, please stop crying.
- Stop it, my dear.
- I stopped.
- Stop it.
Petya is going to show up soon
and you are crying.
- What can I do?
- Exactly, you can't do anything.
Calm down, my dear.
- What should I do to calm you down?
- Nothing.
If you want I can scream
that I love you.
- I love Olga Malakhova!
- Stop it!
- You are crazy!
- I love Olga Malakhova!
What are you doing?
How do you know my last name?
I saw it in your passport.
- You promised not to look.
- I saw only your last name.
Whole city knows
that you love Olga Malakhova.
- Hi.
- Hello.
What have you done to him,
so he's screaming?
I haven't done anything?
Maybe that's my fault.
- Whatever.
- Why are you going at her?
It was a drama here.
I don't like dramas. I prefer action.
Are we gonna stand here?
Let's go.
Let's have a drink somewhere,
orthe girl doesn't drink?
That is not the case.
She just can't sit.
She injured her spinal column.
Congratulations.
You'll carry her in a wheelchair soon.
- She fell off a horse.
- How often does that happen to her?
What a boor!
Olga, please don't be mad at him.
I'm not. He speaks that way
with everyone. Forget it.
- Where are we going to?
Why do you care?
Olga and I, by the way,
are going to Moscow.
We could do it without you.
Olga asked me to invite you.
If that so, why doesn't she speak?
Why don't you speak?
You can't speak either?
- No, I can't.
- Tell me something.
- I'm sorry.
- What for?
For being silent.
Why are you silent?
- I'm just shy a little.
- Don't be shy.
Tell me something about yourself.
Who are you? Where are you from?
And why do you play games
with my simple-hearted friend Alexey?
- I don't play games.
- Hey, leave my girlfriend alone.
- Are you his girlfriend?
- I don't know.
- No, tell me.
- I don't know, I met him not long ago.
You see?
And you said it's your girlfriend.
They are all the same.
- You didn't understand me.
- You got it?
I'm not used to answer such questions,
but why do you disconcert me?
Disconcert? What a word.
Petya, stop showing off. Stop it!
You know what I'm thinking about?
We can drink
while we walk, don't you think?
- What would your mother buy?
- Pepsi.
- Maybe we should buy Chupa-Chups.
- Hey, stop that immediately!
OK, I'm kidding.
The same foryou?
Olya, don't be mad at him.
Actually, he is the kindest man.
I can see that. I'm not mad at all.
- Olya, he is good. Really.
- No doubt.
So why are you so shy then?
You don't say a word. Why?
- I need to get used to him.
- Get used faster or I'll send him home.
I don't want you to quarrel
with yourfriend because of me.
Me and Petya?
We are friends from the second form.
There is no such woman
because of who we could quarrel.
Maybe there is.
Just imagine she is somewhere,
in a toilet, picking her nose.
She is fat and ugly, stuttering.
How lovely!
Olga, do you love me? Just a bit.
- A bit?
- Yes.
Like this.
- Are we going to Moscow?
- Too much time before it happens.
- Come on, let's go.
- Petya is coming. Let's wait for him.
- Alive?
- Alive.
Where is my beer. Give me a spanner.
A spanner?
They've built the city on the swamp. Now
they wonder why there's so much water.
Next time let him go down there.
- Who, Pyotrthe First?
- What Pyotr? Philimonov.
Sorry.
- How old are you?
- 22.
- Why did you tell him and didn't tell me?
- You saw my passport.
I promised not to look at it.
And I didn't look.
This is the right approach.
Any woman would tell me anything.
They are afraid of me.
They feel that I see through them.
- Am I right?
- I think so.
And as foryou, Lyosha,
girls think you are dummy.
I don't care.
Olya, consider me as a dummy.
OK.
- Just like that.
- All right.
And you, Petya, will always be alone.
You'd be so old when you come to us.
Very ugly,
with hair out of your nose, ears.
With ugly glasses. One shoe would be
yellow, the other one - brown.
You'd always complain about your life,
grumble, eat a whole pot with soup,
which Olya cooked.
- She'd knit you a scarf.
- I can't knit.
You'll learn how to. And you'd try
to hang yourself with it and fail it.
The lamp would be broken
and yourfemoral neck too.
And we'd come
to visit you in the hospital,
so cheerful and healthy.
And we'd bring oranges and milk.
You'll be the first
who comes to me to watch football.
Am I right, Malakhova?
No. I think all your life
you'll be single, Petya.
And then you'll marry some bitch,
who will seize the flat, the car
and the country house.
And you'll cook pelmeni foryourself
while she is in a beauty parlour.
Do I look like an idiot?
Not at all. Ljust think that women
are much slyerthan you think.
I don't know why you
considerthem as stupid people.
I don't think so.
I think men are cleverer.
I agree.
Men are cleverer, wiser and slyer.
Look, maybe something will come of her.
- I told you that.
- What did you tell?
I'll examine her,
maybe I will even marry her.
I don't wanna be married.
- You don't?
- I don't.
And she doesn't want to marry.
You idiot! Are you crazy?
- Come on, let's run.
- Maybe he's yourfriend?
Let's go.
Who can do it faster?
Petya, are you with us?
I would never let a woman to outrun me.
Excuse me.
Come on, guys!
Olya, you are so crazy!
We'll leave you in the dust!
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Come on, come on.
Excuse me.
Hello!
Daddy, you are a scum!
Why did you do that?
I'm gonna kill you.
You were about to ruin my story!
OK. I'm going.
All right. Agreed. Bye.
- So?
- What?
How do you find her?
I don't know.
She's got a very sly face.
Come on! Herface is so childish.
That's what I don't like.
Ulyana is enough foryou.
You see a bitch in every woman.
Once in a blue moon I met a normal
girl and you suspect her in everything.
I don't believe clever girls.
Women don't have much brains,
but they have much wisdom.
I'm trying foryou.
Because when you see someone
on the other side of the street
you start thinking
how you're gonna name the third child.
Olya, what took you so long?
I think that was a bad idea
with this climbing.
- I could've broken my leg.
- Look how beautiful it is.
That is where Petya lives.
And there we were walking.
- Excuse me.
- Be careful.
Are you all right, Olya?
Look, it's so great!
Olya, what's happened?
I'll hold you, you hit her cheeks.
- Hit harder!
- I can't!
- Can we help you?
- No, we're fine.
- Olya, are you OK?
- Don't hit too hard.
That's fine. My mother
has the same disease. That's fine.
Olya, are you OK?
- I'm fine.
- You sure?
Don't hit her.
Let's go then.
I'm... just...
- Let me hold her.
- What's happened, Olya?
I saw down, my head began to swim.
- That can happen with anyone.
- It's the first time with me.
- You hinder me. Go straight on.
- Let me hold her.
- How did you manage to faint away?
- I feel so awkward.
Maybe I should hold you?
I'm not sick, I'm not a disabled.
I am all fine.
- Lyosha, go ahead.
- Yes, Lyosha, go ahead.
Excuse me, do you have some water?
- Maybe you need my help?
- No, we're fine.
She is the seventh today.
She looks so big.
Why do they climb
if they can't stand heights?
Thanks God, she has someone to go with.
Thanks God, thanks God.
I don't believe in your God!
And I never believed!
- It's very fashionable...
- Could you tell me where is the exit?
- There.
- This way.
- There? Yes?
- Yes, on the left.
- I wouldn't say so, Galina.
- Do I have to go right or left?
- It depends on where you are going.
- That way, go that way.
But it's betterto turn left.
He makes the sixth round and
hasn't figured out what way to go yet.
OK. Let's continue.
Sauce for hot dogs.
Ketchup.
Correct.
Starts with "K".
- A grunting animal?
- A pig.
Correct. Pig.
- Are you OK?
- I think yes.
I have to start your re-education.
You will swarm up a rope,
do jogging every morning
and afterthat I'm gonna whip you
to keep you in a good shape.
- To whip?
- Yes.
You are not the first
who tells me that.
Many people like this idea.
- Because you look like...
- An unwhipped.
Yes, you're right.
Don't worry,
I'll work on you.
And afterthat I'll marry you.
I like you without re-educating.
Particularly without Petya's.
Maybe Petya's wife would
swarm up a rope and jog.
- I don't think my wife would need that.
- No, I can't swarm up.
- What?
- I can't swarm up a rope.
- Why?
- Wasn't taught in school?
No, I was always free
from physics training.
I was always sick
and I don't like sport in general.
And what about horses?
It's different.
Let's don't talk about horses.
I'm sorry.
Let's go to the embankment.
I love walking there.
Do you mind, Petya?
Stop being so formal. I hit your
cheeks, but you're still formal.
Alright.
By the way, I guess I should
challenge you to a duel
for hurting the lady.
What are you talking about? I came
to her senses and you challenge me?
- I can shoot in the air.
- You mean fart?
Petya, you are a boor.
What are you laughing at?
Why are you laughing?
Do you like soldier's humour?
Olga, I thought you are a decent girl.
- It was really funny.
- Maybe I disturb you?
Maybe I should go home?
I don't know why
Alexey is pitching into me.
I am pitching into you?
This is me who disturbs you?
- Alexey, stop it.
- OK, I'm leaving. I'm sorry.
- Please, Lyosha.
- Why are you so angry?
- Go to hell!
- Look! Awedding.
I don't get it. Why all women
like watching weddings so much?
It's great. Look at her veil.
All men are waiting till they
finish walking and start drinking.
When I will be marrying I will leave
the city afterthe registry office.
You said
you didn't want to get married.
I'll have to.
I'll have to, won't I?
I don't know.
You don't know?
Why are you still angry?
Am I indecent if I understand
soldier's humour?
I love many things.
I love theatre, stars,
films, music, flowers.
- Which?
- Which flowers?
I love daisies.
I don't like roses,
but I do like daisies.
Hold it.
Don't go, I'll be right back.
Where are you going to?
Petya,
if something happens I'll kill you.
Where do you think he went?
- To get flowers.
- Right.
- Real romantic.
- He is too cute.
Are you going to Moscow with him?
I don't think we're going.
You're not sure you're going?
If you are interested,
I gave him money forthe ticket.
Maybe I will go.
- You're playing games with him?
- No. Ljust haven't decided it yet.
That means playing games.
The usual women's thing.
Why does he need
to know about my doubts?
He might be offended.
He'll be offended by other people.
Why do you think so?
I can see that. Because such people
like he are not too lucky in life.
If they succeed in something
they blossom,
but if they fail in something
they fade away.
- Why do you think he's yourfriend?
- Why?
Because you are strong, free.
You are your own master.
When did you manage to study me?
You even talk rudely,
so people wouldn't talk to you.
Actually you are not quite right.
I neverthought about it.
You made it up.
Maybe.
Do you think this makes you different
that you don't think who you are?
Do you fearfor him?
I don't fear, but I feel uneasy.
That's right. So do I.
Do you like him?
A lot.
Ljust have a feeling,
that I'm 10 years olderthan him.
- I don't lie. I wait.
- What for?
That it will pass one day.
He is a child. He is weak.
- A child.
- He's weak.
And are you strong?
No. Strong women is a pathology.
You are not stupid
that you seems you are.
- I'm sorry for being strict.
- That's okay.
I hope you won't tell him
about our conversation.
Why should I?
I don't believe in your wit,
but I believe in your intuition.
- Enter into an alliance with him?
- An alliance?
Yes.
Here's your Romeo.
And yours too.
Daisies don't grow.
Why didn't you take your girl?
Why did you take one from Moscow?
Why do you care?
You care about everything.
Everybody goes to Moscow.
Why do you talk about Moscow so much?
You'd better get married by yourself.
Maybe we'd better get a car.
Aren't you tired of walking?
I hate cars.
- Run!
- Olya!
Wait!
- Where are we going to?
- Does that matter?
- Go and buy tickets.
- Why me? You pay.
- Why me?
- Go, go.
I can pay.
Just a minute, we'll pay.
500 roubles.
- Counterfeit?
- Sure.
Do you have a smaller note?
I often have a dream that
if you jump properly, you could fly.
I fly every night.
That means you're growing.
No, it doesn't.
Many people have such dreams
till they get old, but they don't grow.
Actually, when you grow
you have a dream that you fall.
Do you know,
there are such bumps on the road,
when you jump on the car
it takes your breath away.
Guys, stop whispering.
Here are yourtickets.
- Nowadays we don't have such bumps.
- They patched them.
What's yourticket?
Excuse me.
I have a lucky one.
- You have?
- Yes, I do.
You gotta eat it! Come on!
I need to make a wish first.
Be careful.
Leave it!
Who is yours?
Let me tell you a fortune.
I can tell you
lots of things about you.
Ljust don't have anything.
Are you sure I'll have a rich husband?
We are in a hurry we can't stay.
What did they tell you?
- They told me that I...
- Let's go.
Where are you going to?
Open the doors please!
What's going on, Olga?
Stop!
Come on!
Damn it!
Let's see what we have left.
The phone is here.
All wallets are here.
Check if you have everything.
I don't have a wallet. They took it
from the pocket and I didn't feel that.
Olya, what's happened?
- Guys, it's just great!
- Why do they need my pass?
- Olya, what's up?
- Olya, what has happened?
I can't stand it.
Get up.
What idiots you are! Just great!
What is great?
It's just great, guys!
They swindled us.
We were like three idiots.
So what are you happy about?
We don't have money.
Blockheads! Real blockheads!
We lost our money!
They are actors, real actors.
You amaze me.
Another woman would sob now.
- Why?
- Because we have been robbed.
I can pay you money
to see such performance again.
It's great, isn't it?
- Olya, I don't have any money.
- So what?
Petya you have to work today.
I'll go to grab some beer.
Money is not a problem, guys!
- Buy me a bottle too.
- And one for me.
- You don't drink.
- I do. Yes, I do.
- Want a beer?
After such adventure I want to drink.
Petya, tell him that I'm an adult.
- Olya, are you sure?
- This is my treat.
- Which do you want?
- I don't care.
- Which?
Malakhova, good girl.
I'm gonna drink foryou.
Olga, you surprised me. Be careful.
- Do you still love me?
- I hate you.
- No, seriously.
- I am serious.
- You like Petya, don't you?
- He's nice.
And what about me?
So are you.
Maybe we should leave this place?
- Let's get out.
- He'll get mad.
He'll understand.
- I can't do that.
- Okay, I'm kidding.
It seems to me,
that you speak only to him.
- Are you jealous?
- Even if I am.
Are you serious?
I was trying to be his friend
only to make you feel better.
- For me?
- Yes.
- Really?
- Honestly.
Excuse me.
Hello.
Yes. Just a minute.
Drink this foamy beer.
- Is this one for me?
- No, for Olya.
You can drink, I don't care.
Who does keep calling you?
Different people.
Now a friend called me.
Why didn't you ask herto join us?
She's got flu. She is in bed.
That's why she called.
It's so boring to stay at home.
- Give me the beer.
- Take it.
Let's go somewhere to sit.
It's too dirty here.
You can't sit, Olya.
I forgot.
- Let's go.
- Where?
Let's go to Tuchkov,
to pass all streets quicker.
- Why?
- I don't know. I don't like it here.
My darling, you're not right.
Look at this magnificent cathedral.
Yeah, you're right.
Anyway, I don't like it here.
Some pipes are everywhere.
There are so many pipes here.
Everything honks here.
Especially in spring.
I can always hear it.
By the way, can you whistle?
- What do you mean?
- Using two fingers.
I can.
I can show you.
Did you see that?
I have learned
fortwo months to do that.
All my flat was in salvia.
- And why did you do that?
- For no reason.
Once I imagined that I left my home.
I have lived
in lofts for several months.
So it's a horrible story.
And I got in touch with some gang.
A leader of that gang became my lover.
He was so ugly. He drank.
I can't understand how I lived with him.
But that's not important.
We robbed in a company.
And I supposed to be as an alarm signal.
And since such people
should know how to whistle
I learned how to do that.
Wait, I don't understand.
Are you serious? Did that happen?
No, I made it up.
She told me that she was Bill Clinton,
when she was taking a bath.
It's something special.
What should I do
if I like fantasizing?
I know what you should do.
You should be a writer.
You can write detective stories.
I would believe.
- You can make lots of money with that.
- I have already thought about it,
but I'm not interested,
because I have enough money.
Oh, a rich fianc? E?
Not a rich, but not a poor either.
I inherited a lot from my grandfather.
Actually I haven't got it yet,
but soon I will.
- Who was your grandfather?
- A sculptor.
He was making
Lenin's all overthe world.
Great.
Yeah, he argued with my mother
when she got married to her student.
He was from Mozambique. He was black.
Ever since
my grandfather couldn't forgive her.
And he didn't talk till he passed away.
She got divorced already,
got married my father.
And he inherited everything to me:
The country house, the flat, the car.
I need to wait for a half a year,
so I could sell the flat.
Wait, Olya, why do you have to sell it?
We'll live there together.
We can start even tomorrow.
Well done. She's got a portion.
What have you got?
I can buy a car.
Something like this?
Good car.
No, I don't think so.
Why?
What don't you like?
Because this inheritance
is a very complex story.
I've made this story up 2 minutes ago.
She made it up.
You started dreaming
when she made it up.
I've furnished
the flat in my head already.
Malakhova, you're genius. Cheers.
- To Malakhova.
- Olya, hold on.
Are you gonna lie to me
and I'm gonna believe it?
I don't lie, I fantasize.
I told you that.
- I am a honest girl.
- You are unique, Malakhova.
If you marry him,
let me be your lover.
- You?
- Yes, you'll tell me stories.
It's very interesting.
What are you talking about?
You'll get divorced anyway, my children.
I'll be here, not too far.
- Why are we gonna get divorced?
- First you should get married.
Petya, I don't like your jokes.
Malakhova, he is a very hard person.
He's a romantic, besides that
he's a nervous romantic.
- Sometimes it happens to him.
- Are you serious?
- Me is totally different.
- Because you are a dull.
Thank you, my friend.
Actually I agree with you.
I'm a dull a little.
Is he really a dull?
I didn't notice that.
I thought he was quite clever.
I think intelligence
would ruin my world view.
- Look at Alexey.
- I'm looking at him.
As my grandmother would say:
"Nice head, but belongs to a fool".
Olya, do you believe him?
Look at him. This is a boor.
A man with a very difficult nature.
Mind you, my dear,
someone else is a boor now.
Stop it, guys, stop it!
Tell me I'm a cat or a lamb?
- Do I look like a cat?
- Or a goat?
I don't think so.
Too pity.
I hoped on your intuition.
You know, sometimes
I feel like a poor cat.
- I know.
- People don't notice that.
Excuse me, Pyotr,
can I talk to you for a second?
- Only 3 minutes.
- Where are you going to, guys?
Olya, just for a few minutes.
- Are you going to fight?
- We'll be back soon.
- Petya, what's going on?
- Everything's obvious.
What is obvious?
Are you taking my girl away?
You're absolutely right.
- You are so calm.
- Why should I be not?
Petya, are you insane?
Lyosha, what do you want from me?
- I want you to leave immediately.
- I won't.
You know, I used to call you a friend.
Yes, I still am.
I'm your best friend, you are mine.
Then how can you behave like that?
I behave as I always did.
No. I think it's mean.
What do you want from me?
You want to sort out our relationship?
I don't like such things.
There is a girl.
We both like her. That's great.
- What do we have to sort out?
- OK.
We won't sort it out.
Just wanna know what you think about it.
If that's honestly enough or not.
I meet a girl, start walking with her,
I kiss her and you appears all in white.
You take my girl away
and tell me you are my best friend.
Tell me seriously, why...
Seriously? Want to know seriously?
She's not just my girlfriend.
It's not that ljust like her.
She's not just my woman.
She's made especially for me.
You need another one, stupid. You need
a calm one, who'd only listen to you.
And youngerthan you are.
She's not foryou,
not foryourtemper.
- That means she's foryou?
- Yes.
I understand that. She understands that.
And what's the most important,
do you understand that?
If you weren't my friend
I would've taken her away.
And I would've sent you home.
But since you are my best friend
I'm honest with you. Leave herto me.
You'll have time to play with someone.
You'll fall in love.
And don't smile. I know you enough.
Thank you, Petya.
I got it, you care about me.
A profound bow foryou.
But let me figure out by myself
whom I need and whom I don't.
- You got it?
- I did. I really did.
You are not an obstacle for me.
And I am not foryou.
Let her decide that.
Everything's clear.
- Pyotr.
- Let's go.
I'm not going with you.
- You will.
- I won't.
Come on, it's not polite
to keep a girl waiting.
Son of a bitch.
Why are you alone, beauty?
- Are you sad?
- No.
- I was letting my oldest dream come true.
- Which one?
I threw a bottle
into the water and it's floating now.
Olya, answer me please who...?
Guys, what's going on
on the other side of the river?
Why there are so many people there?
Zenit is playing today.
Zenit? Then maybe we shouldn't go there.
We may be beaten.
- Let's change the bridge.
- Nobody will beat us. I promise.
What time is it?
5 minutes to 4.
Do you hurry somewhere?
No. What time do we have a train at?
- We won't be late, will we?
- Are you going?
I didn't reject such journey.
Are you sure we won't be beaten?
Actually, Petya is right.
Sometimes they hit each other.
But they don't touch strangers.
- Have you ever visited football?
- Of course, not.
We definitely must go there.
Don't worry, ourfans are peaceful.
Spartak is nothing in comparison to ours.
- What did you want to ask?
- No, nothing.
Are you sure?
Do you want me to guess
what you wanted to ask?
I'll whisper it to you
and you tell me if I'm right.
Actually, more than 2 words
one say aloud.
I'll tell you something too.
Go and don't listen.
Anyway, it's a little bit scary.
Don't worry,
do you see how many police officers?
If you were a football fan
I would never let you go alone.
- I would visit all places with you.
- Am I a kid?
Yes, you're a kid.
What if you are arrested or beaten?
I'd worry.
If you're with me I'd defend you.
Hey, you treat me like a mother.
- I treat you like a father.
- I'm not talking to you.
OK, guys. Good bye.
I told you everything,
why are you showing off?
And you don't be a child either.
I'm not. Ljust want...
- OK, Petya, I'm sorry.
- Wait a second.
You don't have to defend me.
That would be so great
if you, Lyosha, were in trouble
and I'd save you.
No, it's much better if you are
paralysed and I'd take care of you.
I would feed you, would...
No, no, wait.
I'd wash you,
I'd read newspapers to you.
You'd understand how faithful I am.
I'd better not to be paralysed.
You'd better be drowning
and I'd save you.
You'd be drowning and I'd save you.
I can swim. Petya!
Your declaration hasn't been accepted.
Careful!
Are you alright?
Then I'd like a Chechen kidnap you.
And I'd save you without forces.
- It's a very bad idea.
- Why?
If a Chechen kidnaps me
I'd be raped for sure.
Who told you that?
But if I'm raped,
I'd have to commit a suicide.
Because I won't be able
not to suffer afterthat.
Your declaration hasn't been accepted.
Let's continue thinking.
Stop thinking.
I'll tell you how it will end.
How?
You'll both
end up in a mental hospital.
- Why?
- And I'll bring mashed potatoes to you.
And take for a walk at the weekends.
No, you won't do that.
- Olga, please, take it.
- Are you insane?
No, take it.
Where are you going?
What are you doing? Stop him!
- Olya, calm down.
- Please, stop him.
- Don't leave us.
- Do something, Lyosha.
Give me my watch back.
I gave you my watch
so you could keep it for me.
- Give my watch back.
- I won't.
- Olya, I changed my mind.
- I won't give it back.
I changed my mind.
Give my watch back.
And at the end of the hour
as usual the traffic situation.
Heavy traffic at Tuchkovy bridge,
at the big avenue in both directions.
Information for drivers.
According to forecast,
heavy rains are expected in the evening.
Be careful while you drive.
Oleg, who Zenit plays with?
I don't know.
I think with Spartak.
I can imagine
what's going to be afterthe game.
Stop it! Yourtickets?
Take it easy.
- Please, let us in.
- Don't worry, we'll step back.
Please, let us in. We'll buy tickets.
I told you it's not scary.
First of all it wasn't you,
it was Petya.
- OK, Petya. Does it matter?
- Now we have justice.
You are so cool.
I didn't expect that. So great!
Football is the most
exciting thing in the world.
- Are you a fan?
- Of course not.
Petya is crazy himself, like they are.
- I'm not a fan of Zenit.
- What team are you a fan of?
- I would tell you, but you'll be beaten.
- Spartak?
Of Brazil team.
That's good. My friend is a fan
of the Brazil team too.
I like a young one.
Sychyov is his name.
He is OK.
Nervous a little, like Alexey.
The star of my heart is Roberto Carlos.
- Who is that you friend?
- A very good man.
You'll meet him one day.
Guys, next time
we're going to football. Alright?
Anyway, you told me
that yourfriend is a horse.
???
No, she really told me about horses.
Let's stop talking about horses.
Isn't that so hard?
I'm sorry.
- I didn't know that.
- You didn't?
So tell me about yourfriend.
Very interesting. When did you meet?
- Stop it. Later!
- I don't wanna meet him.
She trusts you and you don't like that.
No, I don't. Why should I be glad
to her new friends?
- Don't spoil my good mood.
- Where have you got that good mood?
Maybe there was some happiness
in my life.
What did she tell you?
- Stop it, Lyosha.
- What did she tell you?
- I don't ask you what she tells you.
- She tells me that she loves me.
She loves me and not you.
What did you tell her?
She told you that she loves you?
The same what she told me?
- Are you looking fortroubles?
- Stop it, both!
Guys, stop it! Are you insane?
Stop it, please!
This is my fault.
I can explain you everything.
Stop it, guys! Stop it, Lyosha!
You are like kids.
Guys, stop it!
- I'll kill you now.
- Calm down!
Stop it! I can't take it anymore.
What do you want?
Did you tell him you love him?
- Olya?
- What a childish jealousy?
Jealousy has nothing to do with it.
Let's go both.
I can explain you everything.
You both are fools and compete idiots.
Are you going or not?
I'm not going
until you explain me everything.
- Olga, are you with him or with me?
- I'm with the King Elisey.
- What?
- Nothing.
- Stop fooling around.
- I won't.
- Olga, did you tell me that love me?
- Yes, I did.
What did you tell him?
I told him
to behave with you like a man.
And he did. And you were like a kid.
- Really?
- Yes.
Why didn't you tell me that?
Firstly that was not my secret.
Secondly you would've done that anyway.
OK, let's go.
Olya, are you angry?
No, I'm not.
Just don't wanna talk to you.
- But you want to talk to Petya.
- Yes, he's a man. Yes, I do.
- Petya is a man?
- Yes.
- Olga, yes. I'm an idiot.
- Yeah, no doubts.
- I'm sorry.
- Okay.
I told you to calm down.
- There was something else you told me.
- Yes, there was.
Yes, yes.
Olya, you wanted
to tell us something, didn't you?
- Yes, I did.
- Tell us.
I'm sorry,
but I didn't have time to make it up.
Guys, I had to stop you in some way.
- Shit.
- Turn it off.
Yes. What do you want?
I told you. Soon.
You promised not to call me.
That's it.
Don't you understand? Get lost!
- Who was that?
- A relative.
You're too cruel with relatives.
Whatever.
Actually it's great,
when men fight because of you.
That's because you're bad
as all women.
Malakhova!
And all men are idiots.
I don't know about all,
but we both are for sure.
I agree with that.
The only thing I didn't like,
that in films fighters do that nice,
but you both are so red and ridiculous.
You are so good! I'm so proud of you!
- And I'm so fateful.
- Stop showing off, Malakhova!
- Don't do that. Do you hear me?
- I do what I want to do.
It's so great, so great.
- Hello. Yes, yes.
- Who is that? Who is that?
From now on
nobody will call me, I swear.
- Do you want that?
- I want nobody to call you.
Are you crazy?
Let's run there.
Olya, come here.
Guys, I am the happiest girl
in the world! That's true.
Like in an adventure novel.
I'm going to declare my will.
- You are so insolent.
- Quiet. Don't interrupt me.
Lyosha, my baby. You are a very nice,
charming poet.
It doesn't matter
if you write poetry or not.
I don't think you do,
but anyway you're a poet.
I'm very glad we met today.
This is a great luck! It's a luck!
You are the real example of a hero.
It's very rare.
There is not enough
tenderness in this world.
I know that if one wants to be like you,
he should be braver and more courageous.
And you are like you are.
And you have nothing
to share with yourfriend Pyotr.
Because
you and he are the real friends.
Do you realize that?
You and he are the real friends.
Olya, stop it.
Don't interrupt me.
Now you listen.
Pyotr, now you listen.
I want to tell you,
that I'm not insolent.
I'm just proud that such a strong
and brave man paid his attention to me.
Because people like you don't
pay attention to anyone.
Do you realize that you have
the best temper which man can have?
You are very serious,
even though you make a lot of jokes.
But you are very serious to life.
I'm telling you, that's right.
Because you'll win if you are serious.
You will win.
- Will I?
- You will win.
I'm telling you that. Guys!
Guys, I'm so happy!
You can't imagine. I'm the happiest
girl in Saint-Petersburg.
I'm the happiest
Olya, where are you going to?
Olya, we are going to celebrate
our meeting as much as we can.
Follow me!
Olya, where are you going to?
Stop, wait!
Why did you bring us here, Malakhova?
Daddy!
- Who is he?
- I don't know.
- Why did shout at me on the phone?
- Daddy, you got into a mess.
- Why is that?
- You lost, do you know that?
- I always lose with you.
- You really did lose.
You are totally frozen. Totally wet.
Throughout.
I've got a gift foryou.
Is that all?
Do you think that's enough?
This is all for now.
Come on, you gotta change.
- We were in the street, it was raining.
- That's why you need to change.
I wanna drink something. I want Martini.
- Order it, please.
- I'll do that. Don't worry.
- I'm gonna show you them now.
- I'll see them by myself. Come on. Go.
Hi.
- Vsevolod.
- Alexey.
Nice to meet you.
- Petya.
- Vsevolod.
I'm sorry?
She's not allowed to sit.
- Now she can.
- She has problems with her spinal column.
Her spinal column?
What's wrong with it?
- She fell, broke her spinal column.
- In the street?
I forbade herto wearthose hills.
Don't worry. She fell off a horse.
What horse?
Guys, what are you talking about?
She hasn't seen a horse in her life.
She's afraid of animals.
What are you talking about?
- What's going on?
- Take it easy.
And who are you, by the way?
And you?
- Is it an interrogation?
- Just a second.
- Who are you?
- No, wait.
Yes, sure,
I need to explain. I got you.
Guys.
Boys.
We have a wedding in a week.
And afterthe wedding
she wanted to go somewhere.
I wanted to go
to our country house afterthe wedding.
I've got a nice house there.
Very nice house.
And she wants Tibet, the Himalayas.
Mountains.
To walk.
I asked her what she was talking about.
You have to walk in the Himalayas.
You have to walk a lot there.
Heels won't work there.
She doesn't move
in the city except car.
From carto bar, from barto cafe,
from cafe to car again.
And I explained her, there are not
bars and restaurants in mountains.
And there are not cars either.
You gotta walk there. Walk! On foot!
And she is lazy as hell!
She said she wanted to the Himalayas
and she said she would walk.
I won't sit down and bring two witnesses
who tell that I walked and never sat.
So she won. But she is very
stubborn and very persistent.
So we had a bet and I lost and she won.
So that means
you called her all the time?
Yes I did.
Let's be informal, ok?
I called.
And I saw you in the city,
not farfrom the cathedral, in the car.
- I remember.
- You could've hit us.
Stop wrangling, OK?
Let's have a drink.
I have been waiting
foryou for a long time.
Let's have a drink there.
Let's go to the bar.
What are you dreaming of?
What are you gonna drink?
Strychnia, please.
Hey, babe. Look at my back.
Is everything OK there?
- Yes.
- Look, please!
Are you OK?
- Everything's fine.
- You sure?
I don't understand one thing.
Why didn't she tell me at once?
It's logical.
If she had told you about the wedding
do you think you would've walked with her?
I don't think so.
- Very unique.
- Only unique people can survive.
But she is a real unique object.
Let's drink one more time.
One more, please.
Let's bowl. I have a lane ordered.
Then let's go to have a supper.
I ordered a very good place.
My treat. I lost.
You can't even imagine
how much you lost.
Is that a hint or something?
That would be a hint,
but it's too late.
Are you kidding?
Daddy, could've you bought
something simpler?
I think it's cool.
You'll be the most important
at the tomorrow's reception.
- I'm not going.
- Who asked you?
- Yes, you will.
I told you, I'm not.
Guys, why don't you talk?
Does it look good on me?
It's not the word.
You should always wear it.
In the street, to shops.
Forfootball it's nice too.
By the way, Daddy,
take herto a football game.
- She likes football a lot.
- Are you mad at me?
- Me?
- Want a Martini?
- I'm delighted.
- One red Martini, please.
- Have you explained them?
- Two times.
- Guys, I can explain that.
- No, Olya.
It took you a day to explain everything.
I got it, I got it.
- It was a practical joke.
- Yes it was.
- It wasn't a joke. It was a meanness.
- It wasn't a meanness. It was a joke.
When I met you
I didn't think it was going to be so...
You know what she told me?
She always fantasize.
- About her grandfather's inheritance.
- Would you shut up?
She's going to Moscow tonight.
She's going to Moscow.
That's why you returned money.
Like a honesty, nobility.
To play games,
but without money involved.
I even thought that you...
Are you mad at her?
You mad at her?
She is only 5 years old. She's a child.
- You're not right.
- Drink Martini.
She lied to you.
If she made something up,
but only because she believes in that.
Really, she does.
She is a child
and she have childish jokes.
You're not right.
Let's get out of here.
Don't wanna stay.
Don't go into hysteric.
- I don't wanna sit her.
- I've known herfor 3 years.
- You don't know anything.
- But you know a lot, as I see.
Daddy, let's drink this and we'll go.
Cheers.
We present you our condolence.
We really have to go.
You won't go anywhere.
Let's go, Petya. Come on, let's go.
Move it!
Yeah, we are very lucky.
Incredibly lucky.
- An unforgettable day.
- Wait.
- Don't dare to leave.
- I will always rememberyou, Olya.
I didn't know that such people exist.
- Your nerves are really strong.
- You don't understand me.
- Can you listen to me?
- What don't I understand?
- I didn't lie to you, I didn't.
- You didn't?
Petya, I didn't lie to you.
I'm telling that
looking into your eyes.
- Ljust didn't know.
- What didn't you know?
That you are getting married?
You didn't know that?
You didn't know about that?
What are you talking? Listen to yourself.
Listen to me. Stop yelling!
- Guys, is it OK that I'm here?
- I'm real honest. I didn't lie.
Petya, tell him
everything's gonna be alright.
- I swear.
- Quiet!
- Shut up!
- Let me go!
Don't you understand, he's leaving?
- Calm down!
- He's leaving. Can't you understand?
Let him go. It's over.
Calm down.
I really love you.
I love you too.
My sweet girl.
Very much. Everything's gonna be OK.
- We'll go soon.
- Go forthem.
- I told you to go forthem.
- Calm down I told you!
Do you realize that I deceived them.
I'm a bastard, I'm a bitch.
That's OK. Calm down.
- I deceived you too.
- Me? I can forget about that.
It's so good with you.
Run afterthem, please.
- I'm not going anywhere.
- I'm not leaving you.
We'll go and have a ride. Don't worry.
Where do you think you were going?
Are you blind?
What are you sitting there?
Come out and look what you've done.
It's yourfault!
Look where you go!
Where have you got
your driving license?
It's none of your business!
Either I call for cops
oryou pay me here.
What should I pay for? Forthis?
Your car is not worth of my bumper.
You'll pay? What? Me?
- Learn how to drive first.
- You'd better learn, not me.
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.OpenSubtitles.org