RED ARROW
TV CHANNEL RUSSIA
present
With government financial support
from Ministry of Culture of the Russian Federation.
REKUN-CINEMA PRODUCTION
A special thank you to Mihail Prohorov
for supporting this film.
Next.
- May I come in?
- Yes.
What's your complaint?
Cough.
Cough? Strong one?
Yeah.
Dry or with mucus?
Dry one.
- Undress.
- It's hard to breathe.
Ok, I see.
Undressed? Go to the desk.
- Do you smoke?
- Yes.
A lot?
Yeah.
Ohh, you should quit smoking.
Yeah, I know.
Inhale.
Hold your breath.
You can breathe.
Obstructive bronchitis.
Pneumonia...
STILYAGI (HIPSTERS)
MOSCOW 1955
Ivan, Klim, Nikolai...
Come from that side.
Elena, Slava - over there.
Lyuba, give me the tool.
How disgusting!
Raid!!!
Cut-cut-cut!
Get your hands off my shoes!
You don't have the right!
Mels!
Can you walk?
Hurts a lot!
So can you walk?
I'll go fetch the guys.
Don't.
I probably broke my leg.
All because of you.
Okay.
Get up.
Get up, get up.
What's your name?
Mels.
And you?
Polina.
Polly.
For those who know me,
Good Time Polly.
Why Good Time?
You'll see.
Now you know.
Come to Broadway.
You'll have a good time.
What a nice evening...
Why do some people not want to live
like everyone else?
So how did it happen, Mels?
I didn't run her down.
You? The athletic champion
of our department?
I am telling you, Katya...
I stumbled and fell into the water.
It can happen to anybody.
I just don't understand why you are taking it so lightly? "I didn't run her down!"
We are not playing a game of tag here.
Every stilyaga is a potential criminal.
It's only one step
from saxophone to the knife.
Know what, Commissar...
I probably better file a written report
about it tomorrow?
About how I ran, how I stumbled and fell into the water...
Alright, Mels, why are you so?
I was being your friend.
Don't take it so hard.
We'll find that stilyaga door mat.
She won't get away.
The man and the cat are
crying by the window,
Grey rain is coming down
on to the window.
The E.R. is coming
to the man and the cat.
The poor man is sick to his head.
The doctor is coming, coming through the snowy plain.
He is bringing the healing powder
for the people.
The man and the cat will
take that powder,
And their grief and melancholy
will subside.
The man and the cat can
hardly count the days,
Instead of the blue sky
a grey ceiling is above them.
The man and the cat go
flying at night,
But it's only a dream and it doesn't
grow them real wings.
The doctor is coming, coming through the snowy plain.
He is bringing the healing powder
for the people.
The man and the cat will
take that powder,
And their grief and melancholy
will subside.
Where are you? Where are you? The white ambulance.
The man is screaming
inside his shanty abode.
But the walls are deaf,
the pipes are like veins,
And the toilet cistern beats fast
like a heart.
The doctor is coming, coming through the snowy plain.
He is bringing the healing powder
for the people.
The man and the cat will
take that powder,
And their grief and melancholy
will subside.
Where have you been all night again?
On night duty.
Come here, sit.
Don't start again, mom...
Can't you understand that I'll be fired?
That I'll go sweep the yard...
That is if I can be trusted with a broom...
How can I manage people,
when in my own home
I have raised a spy.
For 10 years after the death of your father...
I didn't so much as look at a man.
Where are your despicable clothes?
Where is your American trash?
I'll throw it out! I'll burn it!
I'll make you go naked outside!
You have everything.
What else do you need?
Ungrateful swine you are.
For what did I bring you up?!
For you to flash with your undies from underneath the skirt?!
What are you looking at? What are you looking at?
You, little bitch!
Haven't I whipped you enough? Huh?
I should've beaten you till you bleed!
Tanya, come to Broadway with us.
I've invited you a hundred times.
No. no. I can't.
Alright.
Just look at her!
This is outrageous!
What kind of Soviet woman is that?
Calm down, people! Calm down!
This is not a circus!
BROADWAY
Would you just look at yourself?
You look like a parrot!
Are you a Komsomol member or what?
I work two shifts at the factory!
And here you are idling!
Whoops...
Look, he came all by himself.
Dudes!
Do you have any scissors?
We need to return a favor.
He has nothing to cut there!
At least a clamp of hair
from a mangy mare!
I've been invited.
Who invited you?
Polly.
She called me, so I came.
Well, hello.
Hi.
Are you okay?
Yes.
It seemed to me that yesterday
you slipped a little.
You were seeing things.
Alright.
Bye.
Be careful, you'll get poisoned.
Guard the car.
- Hi!
Glad to see you.
Hi, baby.
Hey, what's this going on here? Huh?
Why are you harassing him?
He's quite a harmless little square.
Let's go to "KOK"!
Dryn! Leave him alone! Let's go.
Hey, guys! I'm with you!
You...
From the height...
Of your beauty pedestal...
Don't notice me.
But...
I'll be able to
Make you
Get to know me better.
Even if today I am a nobody,
Even if they keep telling you
that I'm not the one.
But!
Give me this day,
Give me this night,
Give me just one chance!
And you'll realize,
That I'm the goods.
Give me this day,
Give me this night,
Give me just one chance
You won't sleep
Until I'm with you.
Interested in something?
You can get the rest here.
Password is: "Does uncle Yosya work here?"
Reply: "Uncle Yosya is long retired."
Key words: "I'm from Nolik".
Nolik is me.
"I'm from Nolik, Nolik is me".
And You are from Nolik.
Hey,
Regret...
That you've never met...
Such guys before.
Excuse me, please.
Does uncle Yosya work here?
Uncle Yosya has long retired.
But...
For you...
I'll change myself...
And I'll start everything from the beginning.
Even if today I am a nobody,
Even if they keep telling you
that I'm not the one.
But!
Give me this day,
Give me this night,
Give me just one chance...
And you'll realize...
That I'm the goods.
Give me this day,
Give me this night,
Give me just one chance...
You won't sleep...
Until I'm with you.
Let me go! You have no right!
Quiet, be quiet.
Don't be afraid.
What's your name?
- Bob.
- What?
Boris.
Boris Moiseevich Toiter.
I'm Mels.
Listen, Bob.
I want to ask you something.
Teach me to dance stylish.
Screw you!
Understand, you are the only guy I know among your people.
Oh, really?
It was a nice introduction to be sure.
Is it so hard for you?
Two squats, three claps.
Listen, Bob...
I won't leave you alone.
Bob, you'll be seeing me in your nightmares. Understand?
What is a dance?
A dance is the rhythmic
movement of bodies.
For example, the wien or classical waltz.
Vertebrate dislocation...
- Whose?
- Doesn't matter.
It's a three-beat movement with concurrent rotation around the partner.
Jazz unlike the classical styles is...
Get to the point!
Alright.
There are three main styles: atomic, Canadian and double Hamburg.
Can we skip the theory?
Okay. You're the guy, I'm the girl.
Let's go!
Hands off!
Paw the gals, not me!
How do I do it?
Like this.
First of all.
Where are you putting your hands?
You'll get a slap from a chick, if you're coming on this way.
Start with the right leg.
Hold yourself straight.
Move your legs and do not babble!
Feel free...
- An athlete?
- Yes.
Now squat a little... and twist!
Here you don't need to be
stronger, faster, higher.
Here you need... drive.
An energy. From within.
...I like boogie-woogie and I'm dancing boogie-woogie every day.
To be a real stilyaga,
Buddy, you need to dance well.
You must know what Canadian style is.
It's all serious here,
it's no polka or quadrille.
There's the atomic style and also the hamburg-triple style...
Try to learn it, buddy,
you've got what it takes!
You like boogie-woogie.
You like boogie-woogie,
and you're dancing boogie-woogie every day!
Hello.
Son...
What are you doing in this house
in our absence?
We were just dancing.
In a country where you can't even sneeze loudly
without violating the criminal code...
He is just dancing.
After all, criminal prosecution for
"idolization of  the West" has not been abolished.
Please, look at yourself in the mirror.
Even your hairdo
is in violation of this law.
Alright.
Who was that young man?
My acquaintance.
Why are you so trustful?
Borya...
This young man has the attractive appearance of a KGB agent.
But why do we have to suspect everyone?
Do you know what this is?
And why it is here?
It's the basic necessities for a person imprisoned in a preliminary detention facility.
Uncle Adolf went to prison only because he had a politically incorrect name.
Aunt Fira was arrested...
Because she hung Stalin's portrait across from the bathroom door.
I never even got an explanation for
why I was imprisoned.
But that experience...
I will remember for the rest of my life.
But Dad! It is impossible to live like this!
With this locked door,
with this damned suitcase!
You're a doctor
you should understand!
This endless oppression
may lead to insanity!
- Borya...
- What, Mom?
If you don't care about yourself,
at least have pity on me and your father!
Sonny, the pants aren't too tight?
You should try...
using silicate glue.
Or what if it begins to rain all of a sudden?
Or a street sprinkler goes on?
And... it all falls apart.
- Mels.
- What?
Have you gone nuts?
What's wrong?
A crisis hits USA economy.
Are you going outside like this?
Of course. Or was I unloading night trains for nothing?
Father, tell him!
What? I like it!
We also used to play dress up in the village to scare the girls.
We dressed so freaky,
people would stutter from fright.
Hello.
Hello, Misha.
Hello, Vitek!
You won't see me with a stilyaga!
Alright, Lena, remember that
next time you ask me to fix your bike.
Stilyaga! Stilyaga!
COCKTAILS CLUB (KOK)
- Guys, who are we waiting for?
- I don't know.
Look...
He's looking like a human being now.
As the bourgeois writer
Anton Chehov used to say...
Drop by drop you should squeeze the square out of yourself.
Dude!
"Made in Tambov?"
Remind me, I think I have an extra one somewhere. I'll bring it.
Fred.
Mels.
Betsy.
Came by yourself?
We usually travel in pairs.
It's easier to fight off
squares that way.
Dryn.
Mels.
Mel.
All booked out!
We've paid already. We paid.
Easy, people. Advance reservation.
They're with us. We paid.
Booked out! All booked out.
She's with us too.
Why are you always late?
Let's go twist the atomic.
Are you always so pushy?
I'm not pushy.
I'm determined.
And I'm not a prize cup to be won.
What should I do?
Hey, stilyagi, hello!
We are hang out on Broadway.
Leaving the boring squares behind.
From me you've learned about
jazz and freedom.
I'm the one who tied a stylish tie
on your chest.
Oh, my little babe,
You stay with me.
I'm your playboy.
Oh, my little babe,
Don't you leave me.
My sky lark!
Hey, stilyagi, follow me
Through the forbidden doors!
If they catch us,
I'll solve the problem.
If you don't have a place
to check your feelings with a gal,
For my friend I will lend the keys to a room.
Oh, my little babe,
Stay with me!
I'm your playboy.
Oh, my little babe,
Don't you leave me.
My sky lark!
Oh, my little babe,
Calm down, dudes. Calm down.
We're on Broadway.
Mel, your people.
Hello, guys.
Good evening, Katya.
What does it all mean, Mels?
Nothing.
Hello, commissar, it's me!
Only the costume is different.
You wear one.
And I have a different one.
Just a different one, Katya.
You're worse than an enemy, Mels.
You are a traitor.
Katya, don't start that...
Katya...
- Let's go.
- Katya!
At ease, guys.
Feuf, problem is solved
even without calling my dad...
Hey, dude, do you know where
I can buy a sax?
Maybe you're also interested
in a machine gun?
Interested in a sax?
I am.
If you don't get a deal,
I'm not at fault.
There's a stilyaga.
He's looking for a saxophone.
- Hello.
- Good day.
How old are you, young man?
And you still don't know
what an amazing country we live in?
A bayan is allowed, an accordion is not.
The clarinet
is a politically correct instrument.
But the saxophone
is equated to a real weapon.
Come back in 10 years time...
When jazz will be played
in kindergartens.
And then we'll talk.
Listen, I understood you.
But I need it now.
I have the money with me.
Mamba and twist,
jimmy, foxtrot and tango...
I have played them all many times in my life.
I'm a very high ranking captain...
On the rotting boat having the name of Jazz.
In this country, it would've been better for this boat to be a submarine.
Better to be a submarine!
In this country, doors are closed to Jazz.
Doors are closed to Jazz!
I filled the holds of my boat
with wine and vodka.
Vodka!
But I could never change course.
But I know what this pleasure feels like!
Melody, rhythm, and drive!
When you and your sax become one.
But if you want to learn all this...
And play this music too...
Then play, don't be afraid of anything!
You won't drown!
NEW YORK, BERLIN, VARSHAVA...
Yeah, baby!
Yes, aha, very nice!
Kim.
Kim!
What happened?
Everyone else has normal brothers,
but mine is a stilyaga.
FRED'S PAD
- Good day!
- Hello!
- Such a nice weather!
- It's wonderful!
I wish it'd stay like this for a few days...
Fedya, the food is in the fridge.
I cooked for you
your favorite cutlets.
A salad as well. The shirts for the university are in the wardrobe, clean and ironed.
Study hard. You have exams soon. In particular practice your English.
Okay, Mom.
My poor baby.
Fedya, when you are practicing your English...
Please, try not to be as loud as you were last time. Understand?   - Ok.
Thank you. Farewell.
Girls, keep dancing! You see...
O, Mel!
O, Mel! How are you? (speaking English)
What?
Ok. I'll catch up with you.
So, look here, Mel...
The girls that interest us can be broken down into several categories.
First, there are the real chicks.
There's few of them.
Among the "chicks"
there are the "boruhi."
That's the ones that
do "borayutsya" with our guys.
I hope you understand what
I'm talking about.
Those are fewer still.
Want some?
- There're also the "pink-cheeked loafs."
- "Loafs"?
Yeah.
Their mom doesn't allow them to dress stylish, but they really want to try it all. Got it?   - Yes.
There are also the "squares."
- I know them.
- Great.
Well, there are also the..."rubtsi", "mochalki", "dinamistki"...
Which one is Polly?
Polly is Polly.
That's all. Learn the rest yourself.
Duke Ellington. Mandibular dislocation...
This usually happens,
when a patient yawns too wide...
or takes a big bite out of an apple.
Excuse me.
Come here.
Beautiful, isn't it?
I was walking around here...
I was looking for you...
Why?
There is something I need to tell you.
I love you.
And it's serious.
Very much so...
Alright.
I want to kiss you.
- Hold on.
- What?
- I need to see Sir John.
I need to go use the restroom.
I'll be right back.
Sleep sound at night, Mama,
We are rooting for Dynamo!
Don't be upset so...
Fred, does she have someone?
My advice to you: if it's only for fun,
then find something easier.
It's not just for fun.
Look...
Every one of them... and a 100 more will tell you that they've slept with her...
And every single one of them
will be lying.
Everyone tried,
and everyone... got nothing.
What about you?
I'm a lost cause in all this.
Because my daddy is a diplomat and because I'm studying at MGIMO (diplomacy school).
Because I have a car and this apartment.
But she...
She's Polly.
She always does everything
the other way around.
Listen...
Have you ever... been with a girl?
So, you get a girl in bed with you.
And what's next?
What's so difficult?
Ignorance!
Why do I have to teach you all?
Here. Take this and read it.
Maybe it will be of some use.
But open this only at home, behind a door of three locks. In an emergency, eat it.
The same way a spy eats and destroys his secret addresses. Understand?
(Knock on the door)
Are you alive in there?
Everybody wants to go.
Get out!
Go, go, go!
I see...
I see your eyes once again...
They are a reflection...
Of my love.
The whole world...
I have jokingly turned into you.
Everywhere I see you.
Let everything be exactly as you wish,
Let your eyes shine
as bright as they did before,
I'm with you once again tonight,
Actually... tomorrow night,
If you so desire,
I'll be with you again.
To me it doesn't matter
What day or what time it is.
Time has stopped,
And there is only the sky and
the light in your eyes.
I'm free and happy,
And this song is about how...
We knew life to be so wonderful.
Believe me for the moment,
you'll understand it later.
Let everything be exactly as you wish,
Let your eyes shine
as bright as they did before,
I'm with you once again tonight,
Actually... tomorrow night,
If you so desire,
I'll be with you again.
My friends and brothers!
I will share my happiness with you.
There will be enough for everyone today.
I know that for sure and
I'm not afraid.
I hope that on this stage one day...
just as I'm speaking today...
these words will be repeated
by everyone single one of you out there...
these words about love!
Let everything be exactly as you wish,
Let your eyes shine as bright
as they did before,
I'm with you once again tonight,
Actually... tomorrow night,
Tomorrow night!
If you so desire,
I'll be with you again.
Train, guys!
Let's go!
Come on! Quick! Quick!
Don't turn on the music,
don't use the bathroom.
THE PAD, THE KEY TO WHICH MELS
GOT FROM NOLIK.
The mascara is smudged,
the clothes are crumpled,
Forgotten are school, mom,
and shame.
And a run is coming down
my nylon stocking.
Every prohibition just makes me laugh.
I care not about all those rules.
And only you can I show
how I really am.
The badges pinned on to
the grey jackets,
In people's faces only boredom or fear.
I used to be like everybody else
before I met you.
But life will change now,
We'll walk out this door together,
And we'll be together no matter
what the cost.
The ticking of the clock,
the neighbors behind the wall...
The world will never be the same.
It will be all different
because you're with me.
We need each other like the air and water.
Hello, Mels.
Hi, Commissar.
I actually have a name.
Did you forget?
Hello, Katya!
How will it be in your language?
Katy?
It's just too scary to think about...
Are you waiting for somebody?
For you.
Can I ask you something
as an old friend?
Our record player at home broke down,
and you are the best at these sorts of things.
How will it be in your language...?
Always ready!
Look at this stilyaga! He should be locked up in a cage to scare children with.
Aren't you disgusted to be walking next to someone like that? You are a girl after all!
Maybe you better take off
your Komsomol badge!
Don't torture yourself, Katya. Let's walk on different sides of the street and meet up in front of your place?
No, it's fine.
I just want to know, what do you feel when people look at you that way?
I like it!
It's fun!
You'll fall!
It's great, Katya, when all people
are different.
I'm like this. She's like that.
And you are completely different.
Get down this instant!
Are you able to just walk normally?
- I don't want to be different.
- Why?
Because I don't think I'm better
than other people.
It's not about being better or worse, but just different! Do you understand?
Katya! Do you have a thin screwdriver?
I'll take a look...
Like this?
You are so beautiful, Katya.
It's my mom's.
Do you like it?
I do.
Now you are beginning to look
like a human being.
Thank you.
C'mon, don't take offense!
Look...
Look, how beautiful you are!
Look.
Do you see?
So much has happened!
Can you imagine? Semyon took down an armed criminal, one on one, at the train station.
He had a knife, and Semyon grabbed the blade with his bare hands!
Now he is wearing a cast on his hand.
They even wrote about him in the newspapers!
And I thought you guys
have only us to chase after.
Oh, stop it!
Ivan got married.
To Lyuba. You know her. She's big... She's the one who did the shot put at the sports competitions.
Do you remember?
- Is this interesting for you?
- Sure.
Let's drink some more.
Alright.
To what?
To you!
Do you want me to put
on some music?
You mean this... "Boogie Bones" of yours?
Yes.
I want it!
Katya, what are you doing?
Katya!
What if your parents come in?
They won't come.
I sent them go to the theater.
Katya, have you lost your mind?
That's all that you want from her.
Am I any worse?
So you have decided to rescue me?
I don't need to be rescued.
I'm doing just fine.
But you told me yourself that
I'm very beautiful.
You are very beautiful, Katya.
But I love her. Do you understand?
Who?
That swine?
That prostitute?
You don't even know her.
Last thing I need
is to get to know her!
That's all, Katya. I'm leaving.
I'm sorry, Katya.
Get out! Get out!
Get out!
I'm leaving.
Stop torturing the poor animal!
Come to my office.
Coming.
Fedor, do I call you every time before returning home from the summer villa?
Do you have enough time to
clean up around here?
Yes.
The explain please why in my own office...
I find this "body armor"?
Betsy... I'm sorry, dad!
I understand that one can leave behind a hairpin, a scarf... even virginity...
But how can someone leave without their bra - that I cannot understand.
Understand, Fedor.
One day your mom will find this.
And then I will have all the problems.
I and not you!
- Understand?
- Okay.
I'll be checking everyone
myself personally upon exit.
Hold on. I need to talk to you.
Sit down.
- Did you take any?
- No!
I'll kill you.
Now let's talk serious.
Put that thing away!
Fedor, I spoke to the Deputy Secretary yesterday...
I'll do my best to persuade him...
- to send you to the States for an internship...
- Where? To America?
Hold on.
I want for you to understand that this is not going to be a pleasure trip.
This is the first step in your career.
If everything goes well, you'll come back, finish university. Then go there for a permanent job as an assistant to Third Secretary of Embassy.
Do you agree?
No questions, dad!
- I asked you! Yes or no?
- Yes.
And you are ready to do everything
necessary to make it happen?
Of course.
Okay.
There are 3 conditions.
Tomorrow you take off this clown costume and change into normal Soviet clothes.
Then you go to the hair salon
and change your wonderful "kok"...
to an ideologically correct business cut.
Second.
Tomorrow you will see your friends
for the very last time.
Sorry for the cynicism,
but there are certain rules.
Either you accept those rules or
you go work at the factory.
At your age
I also used to dance in pubs.
And, believe me, that your silly meandering back and forth on Broadway...
is a poorly made parody on what
we had going on!
Childhood diseases need to be had and
overcome in childhood.
And third?
Attention, recording.
Nothing serious. You must marry.
Parting with the chicks. Take 1.
To whom?
Girls, get ready.
If only to Betsy...
What Betsy? Are you crazy?
Betsy!
Fire in your eyes.
Pull in your stomachs and bottoms...
Marry the daughter of academic Kupriyanov.
She likes you from childhood.
Most important:
the feelings, the emotions.
Your mom and I are living together
quite well, right?
He does not need an American wife!
My sweetheart! You're leaving? Goodbye!
I had loved you so selflessly.
You showed me a new world,
a new Paradise,
But now you are leaving it
so inconspicuously.
You're going to be an ordinary
Soviet diplomat,
As if you have forgotten everything
about your past.
But we continue waiting for you, brother.
In your heart you are still a stilyaga,
just as before.
He does not need an American wife!
Let the expensive shoes
be tossed to the side,
Let your hair no longer sparkle
with grease,
But I will not shed a single tear.
Goodbye, my dear!
The man I loved!
Your choice is clear.
Go on, dude!
Follow your father onto
the big highway.
It's a pity that you're leaving like this,
I'm sorry, but we're different,
quite different.
He does not need an American wife!
You'll be able to get a lot in return
From the generous gal
that is called Life.
But never again will you be free,
And the stylish youth will
hardly ever return.
Let's begin, comrades.
Sit down, comrades,
we are starting.
On today's agenda we have the case of
Komsomol member Mels Biryukov.
Mels, stand up!
He used to be the Soviet student Mels.
Now we see before us...
the stilyaga Mel!
It seems like no big deal,
just one letter difference, right?
But let us remember.
What is the meaning of
the name "Mels"?
It is the abbreviation of names
that are sacred to us.
Marks...
Engels...
Lenin...
Stalin...
Now let's stop and think...
What is the meaning behind
the carelessly discarded letter "S"?
He lived among us,
We marched in one column.
He was an honest guy,
He was a simple hero.
But the truth cannot be hidden for long,
The hour has come.
And now his animal grin
has been exposed.
Chained by one chain,
Connected by one aim.
You have dared to encroach on our
sacred sanctum,
Where are your ideals?
You've spit on them!
You sold yourself to the enemy
for bright clothes,
You easily deserted your conscience
and honor.
But you will not win,
our chain will never be broken!
Chained by one chain,
Connected by one aim.
Don't you dare dance to
the fat cat's music!
Don't you dare
to clown and betray us!
Such a person as you should not
be near us,
When we are marching as one.
Our Party is our mother, Komsomol is our father!
Hey, you there, stand still!
Nice! Good fellow!
We will not sing to a foreign tune!
Our joyful bugle will awake us!
Chained by one chain,
Connected by one aim.
There is no place here
for such rascals and vermins,
Here our own ideals
will be left to descendants.
Here our chorus
will sing, rowing down the stream,
Here we march together,
keeping our unity,
We will enjoy going
forward without you!
Chained by one chain,
Connected by one aim.
Are you going somewhere?
I have a bad news, Mel.
Me too.
I have really bad news.
And I have really bad ones too.
What are yours?
I'm leaving,
and we are breaking up.
What's your news?
Then I have...
just minor difficulties.
Polina, what's wrong?
Why are you silent?
You don't have the right
to decide this all by yourself!
You can't decide this
for both of us!
You even can't decide this
for yourself!
I'm pregnant, Mel!
But that's great, Polly.
So we will have a baby.
It's not your baby, Mel.
It's my baby.
Mine.
It's my baby!
Also, my mom kicked me out
from the home.
Well...
It [marriage] is a good thing.
Maybe now you will finally
calm down.
As they say in science...
Multiply a negative by a negative,
and there you have a strong family unit.
So why are you standing
thunderstruck?
Did you hear?
You are going to have
a nephew soon.
Go. Get the beds ready.
It's so strange...
that we don't need to hide anymore.
Polly...
What?
What do you think?
Will we hurt him?
If we...
I don't know.
Right now he is still
very little.
Come on. Come on.
Quick-quick-quick!
Come on, go, dear.
"A Challenge to Soviet Ideology"
"Today You Are Playing Jazz,
Tomorrow You Sell Your Motherland!"
"Playing To A Foreign Tune"
"Monkeys Are Among Us"
"Jazz Is Not Our Music"
"An Embarrassment To Our Youth"
It is a constant. A constant is invariable.
Because usually...
I felt faint.
Let's go get fresh air.
No. It's ok.
Soon I won't be able to
dance at all.
Let's go sign the papers
tomorrow?
Let's wait with the marriage.
Why wait?
Let the baby be born first.
Raid!!!
Mels!
Katya...
Are you serious?
Katya, that's enough.
Let her go.
Katya! I'm really asking you!
Katya!
Don't touch her! Beasts!
You're doing so well!
Should I get a perm too?
I was just planning to cut
my hair today.
But there are queues everywhere. Leave me you number, once it grows out, I'll come again.
By the way, how much does it cost? I'm afraid I may not have the right sum on me.
Miss, can you make it a bit shorter yet?
Just a bit shorter?
Once my hair grows out, I'll come
see you again.
Miss, where are you going, Miss?
Miss, you forgot your tip.
JOHN WAS BORN HERE
Pour some to everyone!
Pour to everybody! Come on! Pour!
Everyone drinks!
Polina! Polina!
Show us the boy!
What are you standing around for, daddy?
Go meet'em!
Polina, show us the boy!
Hands off! Grandfather first...
Who does he look like?
Who?
Oh, my God!
Ours.
Ours!
A warrior!
Our warrior!
His name was Michel.
One of ours?
No, he was an American.
He was walking down Sadovaya Street, trying to talk to somebody to get directions...
But people would all get scared
and run away.
Did you love him?
No. This was something
completely different.
He was like a man from
another planet...
And he was here for only
a couple of hours...
And there's so much you need to ask about them! So much to tell them about us...
But time is running out.
The flight back is so soon!
And we both know that we will never
see each other again.
Is that what you wanted to hear?
Are you satisfied?
A way towards the reduction of
international tension...
Hello.
Well hello there, daughter.
Where are you going, louse? Where?!
You got what you wanted, you slut?
Got what you wanted, you American prostitute?
I've been fired from work everywhere!
I should have killed you!
Miss!
Miss! This is not the way!
Comrade!
Comrade.
Comrade?
I'm no comrade to you!
I'll put you all in prison!
I'll leave you all to rot in there!
Louses! Louses!
Swines! Spies!
Calm down, dear.
Calm down.
How did you name the baby?
Ivan.
Like her father.
Let me look at him at least.
He has our eyes after all.
What's this?
What are you feeding him?
What were you thinking? You have an apartment, but you are keeping him in this thoroughfare?
We have our own room here.
And the second one...
I know what you have here.
30 men use one bathroom, yeah?
Unsanitary conditions, typhus, tuberculosis, diarrhea, jaundice.
Let's go home.
Pack your stuff.
Who needs me now?
Mom, I need you.
Dudes!
Ivan.
No, he's John!
Where is Polly?
Did you hide her from the world?
You men are all the same. First you talk about love, then point to the baby crib.
Betty! Have your own baby first,
and then we'll see.
Oh, God! No thanks!
Knock on wood.
Du-ude!
Hi, Johnny!
Look, a "kok"!
He's already growing one!
A real stilyaga!
I don't know how to hold him.
I love you, baby.
Mom is here.
Listen... Wait around the corner.
I'll be there soon.
Fred...
Mel.
Fred.
Mel!
Fred!
I asked you to be quiet!
Freddy.
Polly. Polly!
Polly.
- Be quiet!
- Got it.
This is for you and the baby.
By the way, the latest achievement of imperialism: the no-spill baby cup.
No matter how you turn it, it doesn't spill.
Don't talk to him about it. He don't even know how to prepare a baby bottle.
He's above all that!
You see, Fred. Polina thinks that to be in accordance with gender equality I too must feed the baby with my breast.
Hey, dudes...
Let's discuss this without me.
I flew to you across the ocean.
I have my own load of these problems back home.
Well, show me the baby.
He's awake already anyways.
How are you doing living with
the mother-in-law?
Do you get along?
In the morning it's lineup.
In the evening - roll call.
He misses living in a communal apartment.
He prefers waiting in line
to use the toilet.
That's him?
Listen Mel, I think you've been listening to too much of Charlie Parker.
Among the slums and skyscrapers and many ads
Americans are walking and chewing bubble gum.
Robbing, killing, humming chu-chu,
And laying with stylish ladies.
Dude!
Hush! I asked you to be quiet!
You know about Bob?
Can your dad help him?
No.
Betsy was evicted from Moscow.
I know.
- And Dryn is in the army?
- Yes.
He is crazy. He want to military office in the whole outfit.
In his shoes, with that hair. So they sent him
to serve on a submarine for 5 years.
Tell about America!
About America...
This is the American style of dress.
What style?
You look like a square.
Why? Look at the quality!
Feel it!
See the label?
It's more important what's on the inside.
The more free a person is,
the more simple his dress.
Mel...
I have bad news for you.
There are no stilyagas in America.
What do you mean?
It's just so. No stilyagas.
If we walked down Broadway
dressed like this...
down the real Broadway...
we'd be taken to a nut house
after walking two blocks.
Mel, try to understand.
There are no stilyagas there.
- Get lost.
- Mel!
- Get lost!
- Mel.
Go to hell!
But we exist.
Mister, please don't kick us out of
the building hallway.
We will no longer sing loudly.
We will no longer drink, cuss or smoke.
And if you want to do these things yourself,
then don't invite us.
Today we are saying goodbye...
I thought we had a reserve of
at least another 5 years.
I was so sure that we had enough time to drink beer and chat.
But I already see your back, as you are departing
with a sign saying "Don't miss me".
Wait! Stay for at least one more day!
Go on, play on!
Goodbye, my dear friend.
You are leaving so suddenly.
Go on, play on!
You are leaving without
saying goodbye.
You are leaving so unexpectedly.
Well, goodbye, my dear friend.
Go on, play on!
You know, it's all really not so bad.
This style defeats fear.
This amazing, difficult, absurd epoch...
Did not turn us into dust.
Let us remember all these faces...
And the sharp edge of a vinyl disk.
And may Love save us all!
Go on, play on!
Goodbye, my dear friend.
You are leaving so suddenly.
Go on, play on!
You are leaving without
saying goodbye.
You are leaving so unexpectedly.
Well, goodbye, my dear friend.
THE END
Mels - ANTON SHAGIN
Polly - OKSANA AKINSHINA
Katya -EVGENIA BRIK
Fred - MAKSIM MATVEEV
Bob - IGOR VOINAROVSKY
Betsy - EKATERINA VILKOVA
Dryn - KONSTANTIN BALAKIREV
Father of Mels - SERGEY GARMASH
Father of Fred - OLEG YANKOVSKY
Director
VALERI TODOROVSKY
SUBTITLES WRITTEN BY:
Katia Kutyavina (Seattle, WA, USA)
e-mail: djkatish@gmail.com